Chapter 37: Wargames, Pt 3

"Disguise yourself, but remember where the disguise ends and self begins." - Lucius Malfoy

The Drawing proceeded briskly with a separate barrel for each house and no pause between students, unlike the Sorting. Students moved quickly to their barrel, thrust in a hand, pulled out a stone and with a flash their robes changed to announce their faction. The drawing started slowly, but after the first students' robes changed the effect felt routine. Now people moved along steadily as yet again the magical became mundane. A few minutes into the Drawing there was a brilliant green flash, brighter than normal, and everyone stopped chatting. Percy Weasley's brilliant robes had acquired a prominent green sash and locket. The first leader had been revealed.

The twins let out a groan. "Come on, Purple!" drawled Fred or George, to great laughter.

"Hurry along," said Headmistress McGonagall, standing at the lectern overlooking the four rows of students moving slowly to the barrels, "We haven't all night."

Draco sat next to Gregory, it would take about fifteen minutes before the older students finished. Gryffindors just rushed their barrel, Hufflepuffs moved in an orderly fashion that made sense to them, and nobody understood the Ravenclaw system. Slytherins queued by seniority and the fifth year was up. Another flash and everyone turned to see Lesath Lestrange wearing the purple sash of leadership.

Lesath blanched slightly then returned to his seat. Other students in purple robes moved to join him but nobody spoke once they'd selected their colour – Professor Lockhart had indicated that the stones had several charms on them (apart from the robe-changing charm) to ensure fairness. Students who picked later weren't at a disadvantage for plotting. The room grew quieter as people selected. Draco thought it imbued the process with the dignity it sorely needed.

"Lesath as leader, huh," Gregory said. "He looks like he's going to be sick. What will we do if we get Purple?"

"Follow Lesath," Draco said, automatically. About a quarter of the people's robes gave no obvious sign of any change. They could be civilians, such as he'd been in the Autumn battle when he'd lost his arm. Or perhaps sleepers. Draco reminded himself that some people who had purple robes were probably secretly green, and vice versa.

Professor Lockhart stepped up to the lectern. Apparently with half the students sitting mutely the room was quiet enough for him.

"While we're still picking, I'd like to say that the rules are simplicity itself," Professor Lockhart said. "Each side has four leaders, and when all four are dead that side has lost. In order to make up for the relatively vast differences in spell casting power, the only spells that can be used are Somnium and your Patronus, for those who can cast it. That means that everyone is on roughly equal footing with seventh years. Those are the basics, but the rules are not simple. For example, some individuals will be allowed more complex spells, and they'll know who they are. Rest assured that these individuals, like the leadership sashes, are determined randomly. Casting a spell that you know in real life but not in the game will lead to disqualification. To ensure that this particular War doesn't take longer than the weekend, there will be some rules that come into play around lunchtime Sunday, to speed things up. Should it come to that."

"Additionally you will all receive tidbits of information, mostly true."

Draco glanced behind him and saw Harry Potter smiling gleefully. Draco hadn't been wrong, at the beginning of the year. Harry really did love the battles, but had withheld himself out of them for some reason. But with an all-school war, Harry was involved again. Why had he denied himself the pleasure? Was this part of Voldemort's curse that Hermione had mentioned? That didn't make sense, he'd have to sit this fight out as well. Perhaps Harry had solved the curse. He hadn't said anything. But Draco could see Harry's joy and Harry, seeing Draco, gave a nod and a thumbs up, then held up his hand to his heart and rubbed his fingers across his chest diagonally, then pointed to Lesath.

There was still the Green leader for Slytherin and they were almost done with the third years. Draco shrugged, it's not like he could control the selection, so what was the point of worrying or hoping? Draco and the rest of the second years got up, Professor Lockhart still talking.

"...because, of course, while duels win battles, good intelligence wins wars. So there you go. Also, based on some feedback I've decided not to institute detention for those who died, unless you get disqualified. However, only members of the winning tribe will be invited to the victory feast, and I'm told the House Elves will really outdo themselves for dessert."

Draco's turn was up and he quickly reached into the barrel and grabbed the first stone, as his fingers closed around it his robes flashed to Purple. Gregory went after him and also got Purple. Draco went back to his seat, head turned, watching the line. Harry was almost up.

The Green Leader still hadn't been selected. Worrying served no purpose, but Draco couldn't help himself. Just my luck to have Harry draw it, instead of me. Actually, that wouldn't be so bad. Draco started to work out the possibilities. In many ways it would be refreshing, fighting Harry as part of a game, but a quick flash revealed Harry without any special markings or sash. Just green robes.

Harry took in stride and went back to the green side of the Slytherin table. Most of the houses had naturally divided themselves into their respective two sides. Draco glanced around the other tables, it seemed that seven of the leaders had been selected, and he didn't know any of them well. He knew Marcus Belby, the Purple Leader for Ravenclaw, somewhat. Glancing at the Gryffindor table, he saw that Hermione's hair tumbling across the shoulders of her green robe.

The Slytherin first years were drawing their stones and – with a bright flash – Colin Creevey blinked several times and stared down at the green sash of leadership, before breaking out a huge grin and practically skipping on his way back to the table.

Now that's interesting, Draco thought, He'll just go to Potter for advice. It's like Harry being in charge, but with a delay.

"I see that we are about done. Some final announcements. Once you get back to your room, there will be mail delivery, you are all familiar with the procedure. You'll be given a few minutes to digest any information you receive. At the signal, the war begins. And remember, no spells can be cast by you or at you when you are at home."

Several students tried to say something, but nothing came out. Ginny Weasley frantically jumped up and down but Professor Lockhart shook his headwhile taking out his wand. "Since there are no questions," he said, smilingly, and he waved his wand over the crowd and said a chant that Draco couldn't quite make out.

Draco found himself sitting in his own bed. He lifted his head and saw Gregory and Harry's bewildered looks.

Harry looked up, shock of disorientation fading. You can't apparate in Hogwarts which begged the question of what had just happened. The easiest way would be to just false memory charm everyone to go to their rooms and forget the walk. Had any time passed? Harry glanced down at his watch, and sure enough it was almost 7:30. Nearly fifteen minutes missing. Harry gritted his teeth, false memory charms should be banned, although this one – if it was one, and not some more powerful, subtle spell – seemed harmless enough. Just overly dramatic.

In any case, Harry's more urgent concern involved leaving the room alive.

"Well, that's another fine mess you've gotten us into, Draco," Harry joked. Gregory looked sharply over at him, while Draco cocked his head slightly, watching Draco.

"Vene lalare bokor sohap hewelog baramie tomotim ciep toluwan wi?" Gregory said, looking at Draco. Draco now turned his head towards Gregory, but kept his eyes on Harry. There was something in how he was watching them, Harry recognized that Draco was plotting. Already.

Draco shrugged and said, "Na cinarieg rietiehi arepod erusitot Petter huger hihulog." Harry thought Petter may refer to him. Apparently Lockhart had cast another spell to make the two teams unable to understand each other. That … made sense. Draco said something to Harry, the intonation sounded like a question, but Harry just shook his head No and raised his hands in a helpless shrug.

Often warring factions would be co-located, but separated by different native languages. Perhaps Professor Lockhart had used some warring tribes model, like some of the brewing European conflicts that the Muggle Parliament fretted about. Another way to differentiate the two factions. But had Draco said his name?

"Gregory," Harry said, loudly. Gregory looked over. Draco and Gregory exchanged a few phrases.

"Herry," Gregory said.

Harry nodded and pointed to himself. Then pointed to Gregory and said "Gregory," and then pointed to Draco and said "Draco." This experiment probably helped them more than it helped me, oh well. Harry eyed the room. He was closest to the door and if he dove for it once the war started he'd probably be able to make it out. Draco and Gregory spoke quickly and he didn't recognize any more names, so they'd probably stopped referring to people directly. Definitely helped them more than me.

Well, that wasn't necessarily so bad. They were involved in a wargame, but just a game and not necessarily zero-sum. In the strict sense, there could only be one winner, but if the process enhanced the prestige of everyone in the room that would be a nice benefit. Still, no more experiments. Harry considered the problem of escaping. Then he kicked himself, and got up out of his bed. Gregory and Draco instantly had their wands out, but then stopped.

The war hadn't started, not yet. There'd been no mail, and no signal. Harry took a few steps towards his chest before Draco and Gregory were up, collecting items from around the room and tossing them onto their beds. Harry went into his trunk.

Harry already stored emergency equipment in his pouch, but took a quick inventory just to make sure it hadn't been tampered with. He'd witnessed the fall battle in the lake, when the other young Slytherins had been abducted without any gear. He still had everything he expected. He grabbed a vial of Polyjuice and put it carefully into his pouch. It probably wasn't worth using now, but 'Be Prepared' rang in his head. Harry felt guilty, but there were no rules against it. He certainly wouldn't use anything unreasonably powerful, nothing whose existence he dare not reveal. Harry considered leaving the potion behind, just to keep himself from being tempted, but Polyjuice potions were merely expensive, not rare. He packed it in his pouch. It probably belonged there in any case.

Harry heard the flutter of wings and raced out of the trunk and jumped onto his bed. The owls had dropped off their letters and were already back at the window.

Gregory and Draco were hastily shoving spare wands into holsters. Draco had changed into his more formal robes, but they'd apparently changed colour as soon as he put them on.

"That was a good idea," Harry said to nobody. Draco looked over and Harry pointed to Draco's robes and then laughed. Draco just shook his head, and there was something odd in the way he was acting. Draco had been sleeping poorly, even Harry had noticed. He may just be tired. That was another important discussion to have.

When he could talk to Draco.

Harry Potter opened up his letter:

Daphne Greengrass (who wears a neutral robe) is secretly loyal to green.

You are allowed to cast Expelliarmus, in addition to standard spells. If you cast this on your leader successfully, you steal the leadership stash. (This is true for anyone).

The purple leader of Slytherin is immune to Somnium.

You may summon a house elf once every twelve hours to bring a small set of rations by loudly asking for "Emergency Food, please!". Only one student in ten has this ability. If your house elf is shot by a spell during this time you lose this ability.

Harry chuckled at the last one. He could summon the house elf already, but this made sense in game. In real wars lack of food was a confounding factor. If this went for a full two days some students would be able to dole out food. Nobody would be in danger of starving, but it would add level of stress. Harry wondered when the twelve hours reset. In any case, he had a full pouch of Granola bars and bottles of water, but he'd never planned on supporting multiple people for days. That was a gross oversight, he'd stock up and buy several weeks worth of rations for a small team. Just in case.

Harry went back to reading.

There are twelve traitors.

Harry considered this. Roughly three traitors per house, one or two each side, if they were divided evenly. Which meant that he shouldn't worry about traitors too much. From a strictly numerical point of view most people wouldn't be a traitor. Giving this information wasn't unrealistic. In a real battle you'd have to worry about this. However, as a simulation, Harry had to admit it worked pretty well. It gave him a rough estimate to work with. A base error rate. Paradoxically, rarer traitors could do incredible damage if everyone automatically trusted everyone else. If everyone suspected everyone else then the resulting security level would supress traitors. But with so few, security would (in most cases) be counterproductive. The classic tradeoff. Harry decided to focus on rooting out the (approximately) one and a half traitors wearing green Slytherin robes.

His first step: discover if there were passwords for the purple traitors secretly loyal to green. Presumably Colin would be given that information. If not, he could ask around. There was no reason that purple and green would have symmetric security measures, but those kind of things often happened, in simulations.

What else did the letters imply? Assume each student got three to seven facts of information, even if they were all duplicated several times – they probably were, so people could separate fact from fiction - there were still hundreds of facts in this game. Again, this worked as a realistic simulation. In the real world you wouldn't necessarily know many details about your enemies.

This was going to be fun.

He read the rest of the facts, which dealt with who he could trust from other houses. Harry read the scroll several times, once again wishing there was a spell to give him Hermione's perfect recall. Suddenly there was a loud roar echoing throughout the halls that set his teeth on edge and Harry's scroll – along with Draco's and Gregory's – crumbled, the pieces of paper blown out the window by the fading echoes.

Harry took out his wand. Draco and Gregory did likewise.

"It occurs to me that I could do a lot of good keeping the two of you bottled up in here," Harry said. "I mean, if it was just Draco and me, I'd probably be better of going. But you've got a broom, Gregory, and I don't imagine that they've suddenly made you a bad flyer. You could go tearing around the hallways, picking people off." Harry kept flicking glances between Gregory and Draco. Draco looked puzzled, probably trying to figure out what Harry's game was.

"But where's the fun in that?" Harry said and jumped up and raced for the door, wand out. Draco fired at him but nothing happened and then Draco was jumping behind his bed - putting it between them as a shield - but Harry was already out of the room before the first Somnium was cast. He laughed at Draco's shouted word, even a Babel spell didn't mask his meaning.

Author's Note - The gibberish above is just gibberish. Not code or anything.

Chapter 43: Pressure

Harrod Xavier Realgar sat at his post in the Ministry of Magic, humming happily to himself. The Ministry was practically deserted, as you'd expect on a Saturday, so he could actually get work done instead of simply running errands for the Assistant to the Undersecretary. Esmeralda Beery-Malbolges - said Assistant to the aforementioned Undersecretary - took perverse delight in ordering Harrod around during the week so he inevitably fell behind in his work. He'd volunteered to work Tuesdays through Saturdays, which not only earned him praise – and a fifteen percent shift differential! – but provided one sane day without other bureaucrats pestering him for minutia.

Harrod didn't think of himself as a bureaucrat, no! Harrod Xavier Realgar was a dedicated civil servant. When he'd been at Hogwarts (it seemed so long ago) even his fellow Hufflepuffs had commended his work ethic and his almost five years at the Ministry hadn't damped his spirit. He worked hard. Tasks placed in front of Harrod were more tedious than unpleasant, and it was for the betterment of society. And with the recent changes there were opening for promotions and he fully intended to grab one.

Harrod had been filling out the appropriate paperwork to allow for the import of several hundred Romanian Ivory-Plumed Chickens for the Haruspectors when he heard footsteps echoing down the hallway in front of the reception desk. During the week Harrod sat at his own desk, but when they were short-staffed, such as today, clerks worked in the hallways so that they could guide visitors. And also ensure that visitors didn't stray outside of the public areas.

A man in ill fitting robes, with wild hair and mutton chop sideburns that marked him as either a powerful Scottish wizard or doddering fool walked along side an immaculately dressed boy with slicked back blond hair. Harrod smiled as they walked up to the reception desk, carefully setting his paperwork aside, and said "Good morning" quite cheerfully to the pair.

To his surprise, it was not the man who answered, but the boy.

"Good morning to you, as well. This is Professor Isaac Asimov of Hogwarts, and I am Draco Malfoy. I'm not entirely sure, but I believe that our appointment is just down this hallway, can you let them know that we are coming?"

The boy had pointed to a room slightly down to the right of the hall, a non-public area. And at no point had he stopped walking. During his speech he'd made a small bow of introduction, but continued steadily toward the door. He gave no indication of stopping. The man next to him had stopped at the desk, but then quickly started after the boy. The boy's actions startled Harrod so much that he answered before the name sank in.

"Excuse me! Ah, pardon me Mr. Malfoy," now that the name had sunk in Harrod stood up from the desk. "I don't know exactly who you are meeting."

"I wish to be escorted to the Hall of Prophecy. It's past that door, I believe."

Harrod blanched inside, but didn't show it. He'd heard of the Hall of Prophecy, everyone had heard of it. During his first week he'd been sent to get a left handed wand, had to clean out Boggart cages, and been ordered to the Hall of Prophecy. All standard practice, hazing the new guy. Everyone gave him different directions and he'd never been let in. Visitors were not allowed in the Hall of Prophecy.

Perhaps they had been, once, centuries ago. Outsiders weren't even supposed to know it existed. Harrod knew about the Hall, every clerk knew that Merlin had built the Halls somewhere in the Ministry. But where? Well it must be in a restricted area and clerks with less than a decade's experience did not travel in restricted areas or ask about them. At least, not if they wanted to stay employed.

"Who did you say you are meeting again, Mr. Malfoy? We don't get many requests for that, and I'm not exactly sure what to do, if you'll forgive me."

"I'm not exactly sure how things are organized, now that Amelia Bones is running things. The Hall of Prophecy should be under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Divination, Scrying and Prediction. Secretary Etain Levalsior."

This time Harrod blanched on the outside. He'd expected the boy to name Esmeralda, or some equivalent clerk. Maybe the Undersecretary herself. Because Esmeralda bossed him around, he'd gotten some face time with Undersecretary Laurensdotter, Technically she was five levels above him, in the Ministry's Organizational chart. The boy had named the Undersecretary's boss. The man shifted his feet but smiled broadly, and seemed genuinely interested in the conversation, but hadn't said a word.

"I don't know if I should bother Secretary Levalsior," Harrod said.

"Nor would I expect you to," Draco replied. "The Hall of Prophecy is open to anyone. Merlin himself established it so that anyone who wishes can listen to a prophecy about them. Some busybodies have restricted access in recent years. You undoubtedly learned that from Professor Binns when you were at Hogwarts. I'd expect that most Gryffindors would have forgotten, but a Hufflepuff like yourself wouldn't forget."

"I haven't, of course," Harrod replied. He didn't exactly remember that lecture, nobody remembered much from Professor Binns. It did sound vaguely familiar. He wondered how the boy knew he was a Hufflepuff, as he'd long ago given up the childish habit of wearing house colours, then glanced down and saw that he'd put his nameplate on the desk, since he was working reception. Members of Noble Houses knew people at the top of the organizational chart, not at the bottom. He looked back up and saw the boy's piercing grey eyes had never left his direction.

"I happen to know that even when it was officially closed it was still open to people in good standing who had valid concerns. I assume there are procedures in place. I don't expect you to contact the Undersecretary, merely follow protocol. No need to involve anyone in this at all, beyond the escorts and security. Whatever else is normally required. You do know protocol?"

"It's never come up," said Harrod.

However, there was a protocol for answering unexpected requests and Harrod knew that one backwards and forwards. "But I can look it up quickly, one moment." He dove behind the desk and found a large tome, not bound in leather but in wood, a soft wood that reminded Harrod of days he'd spent outdoors, especially during his summer vacations. The man and boy talked quietly amongst themselves, idle chit chat about something called Movings, and Harrod whispered "Protocol for Visiting the Hall of Prophecy" and the book flung itself open, pages hissing and howling like an angry cat fighting its bath, then there was silence as Harrod read:

Protocol for people requesting to visit the Hall of Prophecy

Revision 10, effective July 1, 1992.

Get rid of visitors using any excuse necessary, then file a confidential report directly with the current Secretary of D,S & P.

Harrod looked at the book, then realized he didn't have any idea how to get rid of these visitors. Any excuse would sound like ... well, an excuse. And he'd just admitted to not knowing about the Hall of Prophecy. "Show me revision 9, please." He looked up at Draco, made a shrugging motion and the boy nodded and continued his conversation about an exciting battle about a whip-wielding Wizard trying to recover a strange artifact. Harrod scanned Revision 9 - dated 1871 - which had a much more convoluted process, almost all of which resulted in the same outcome as Revision 10, but left a slight hint at entrance.

That would do quite nicely.

"Ah, Mr. Malfoy. Unfortunately parental approval is required for minors. Professor ... I'm sorry what was it?"

"Asimov," said the old man, a bemused smile on his face.

"Asimov, right. As Professor Asimov is not your parent, I cannot let you in."

"Quite reasonable," said the boy. He made no move to leave and instead reached inside his cloak and pulled out a mirror. Harrod had seen Aurors using that model and he smiled as the boy held it up to his face and chatted into it. He then walked back to the reception desk, the first step he'd made away from the door, and his shoes echoed across the hard marble floor. He held out the mirror so that Harrod could see it.

"Good morning, this is Lady Narcissa Malfoy." The woman in the mirror smiled elegantly, her long blond hair draped across her shoulder. The family resemblance would be obvious even if he didn't recognize her from the articles last summer in the Daily Prophet. Despite her age she still looked more enticing than the clerk from Amulet Inspection that Harrod had been meaning to ask out. It would be easier to date if I didn't work Saturdays.

"Lady Malfoy. I am Harrod Xavier Realgar, clerk of..."

"Herbert Beery's Grandson?" she interrupted sweetly.

"Yes, Lady Malfoy, and as I was saying," he started but she interrupted again.

"Well, then you know who I am and this simplifies things. I of course grant you permission to escort my son Draco Malfoy of the Most Noble and Ancient House of Malfoy" and at this she rolled her hands to signify that she was dropping the rest of the tedious formalities, "to go listen to any and all prophecies concerning him in the Hall of Prophecy. There."

Draco turned the Mirror to face him, and said "Thank you, Mother. Although...," he peered over the mirror and spoke to both of them. "It occurs to me that someone may not believe you did this. We can hardly expect people to accept you word for so formal a matter over a mirror. Bureaucracy likes paperwork. Shall I have a formal letter sent? It wouldn't take but a moment."

The last was addressed to Harrod.

"No, that won't be necessary, I consider the parental release satisfied," said Harrod. Draco put away his mirror while Harrod read further down the list. "Ah, I'll also need approval from a member of the Wizengamot." He smiled apologetically. Not because of the protocol, but because of his deception. Harrod felt guilty stringing along the boy, who had been so polite.

"Do you really wish me to disturb the Lady Malfoy again?" said Draco Malfoy, reaching back into his cloak.

"Ah, no, of course not. I'm sorry, I should have been clearer. The visit must be seconded by another member of the Wizengamot. Technically the Lady Malfoy made the request for you, so she could not second it."

"Honestly, I don't remember any of that from the class, but I suppose they don't mention all the details you have to keep up with. And, if I'm being honest, I fall asleep in Professor Binn's class fairly often. He's not interesting, like Professor Asimov. But that does seem like the sort of thing they'd require, I mean who can forget the rulings of the third session of the one-hundred-ninety-ninth Wizengamot reforming Auror Interrogations?"

During this speech the boy had walked back halfway towards the door and taken out his wand, which set of a minor panic although that was silly. No twelve year old boy would attack someone in the Ministry of Magic, that would be foolhardy. Draco Malfoy made no move towards Harrod, he'd been talking to him at an angle, and he lowered his stance slightly and moved his wand with precise whipping motions and Harrod - who didn't know the one-hundred and ninety-ninth Wizengamot from the whatever number they were currently on - did know a bit about Auror Interrogations. He'd gone through one as part of his hiring and that boy hadn't just been spouting gibberish: Auror interrogations could be overruled - or at least delayed - by members in good standing, as long as you had a second and a Harrod felt a nervous dread. This boy, barely half his age, had a casual command of facts he shouldn't know. But once Draco started his spell Harrod's nervousness transformed to surprise. He can't possibly be...

And then Draco Malfoy cast "Expecto Patronum!"

A silvery snake – Harrod wasn't sure of the type, but it looked large and hungry – floated just above the ground in front of Draco, and Professor What's-his-name took a keen interest in it, too. He'd seemed surprised, and taken a shuffle step backwards before recovering.

"Please go to Augusta Longbottom, give her my respects, and kindly request her to join me in the Ministry of Magic. She should still be in Diagon Alley, where we met at that small gypsy bistro. She should be finishing up with lunch shortly, but if she is still eating she should by all means finish."

The snake nodded sharply and slithered away at astonishing speed. Draco put his wand back.

"What are the other requirements, Mr. Realgar?" Draco had pronounced his name correctly, Ree-Owl-Gahr. Most people got it wrong on the first time. "It occurs to me that we have ten minutes or so before the message reaches Lady Longbottom, and it might be another thirty minutes. It would save considerable time if you would kindly enumerate all the requirements now."

"Uh, Mr. Malfoy," Harrod said.

"Lord." The voice was still high, a boy's voice, not a mans. Draco hadn't dropped it into a false bass voice, like children sometimes did. The voice was no colder than before. There was no acting in it, no drama. But the word hung out there. Harrod cast his glance to the Professor, and the man was looking at both of them in open bewilderment. Harrod could press the point. Draco Malfoy was not technically of age and while some students had achieved their majority by appearing before the Wizengamot over the summer, he had not.

Harrod did not feel inclined to press the point.

"Lord Malfoy, I'm afraid there are extensive requirements."

"Understandable. You must follow protocol and I hardly blame you for that. Exactly how many requirements? If you would let me peruse them that would save time."

"I'm afraid that's against policy."

"Then please just enumerate them, it may be that I've forgotten something although I think you'll find I'm reasonably well informed about this. But if I did forget something, I'd like to know so that when I come back I possess a full and accurate list of what is required. It seems foolish to not simply show me the list, since I'll have to fulfill all of these requirements in any case. I can read it and let you do some useful work in the meantime. I have plenty of time, and your shift doesn't end for five hours."

Harrod's mouth felt dry, and he cast around his desk for his glass of water and took a sip.

"If I can ask, what's so important? Why do you need to go into the Hall of Prophecy?"

Harrod could see Draco considering it. He'd have never asked under regular circumstances. Harrod worried that something in his demeanor revealed that he was grasping at straws. He took another sip of water to hide his nervousness, and the Professor tilted his head. Now that Harrod thought about it, the entire setup was odd. What was a young student doing out of Hogwarts during term? How had he managed that? And trying to be the first outsider to go to the Hall in centuries (Was he the first? The protocol existed, and if any family could bend the rules and get access, a Noble and Most Ancient House certainly could). If Harrod could just slip away he'd send out queries or call in a senior clerk and make this someone else's problem, but he dare not leave. While thinking, he considered the Professor. The man must be the new Professor of Muggle Studies, everyone knew Gilderoy Lockhart and this man clearly wasn't him. Why did a Slytherin, and a Malfoy at that, associate with him?

And since when could a Slytherin summon a Patronus? Harrod gulped his water. Lord Draco Malfoy apparently made up his mind and strode back to the reception desk, his right hand held up in a fist. No, not quite a fist, his hand was slightly open, at shoulder height like a salute and spoke firmly, in a commanding tone:

"Sigil Prodi!"

And a cane appeared in his hand, a silver snake head peering over the top of Draco Malfoy's grasping fist.

"Mr. Harrod Xavier Realgar, this is the cane of Lucius Malfoy, son of Abraxis Lords of the Noble and Most Ancient House of Malfoy and even if you didn't recognize me I can tell by your eyes you certainly recognize it. I shouldn't be holding it. This Sigil should not answer my commands but it does because Voldemort murdered Lucius Malfoy last summer, and now I am Lord Malfoy. I was almost murdered last spring by Voldemort or one of his agents."

Harrod's eyes followed the head of the cane that Draco Malfoy had been slowly lowering to the ground, moving it gently into position as if it were not some relic of power, but just a normal walking stick. Harrod would later swear to everyone who would listen that the cane's eyes followed his and that they narrowed slightly, with growing anger, as Malfoy spoke. The dread that Harrod Xavier Realgar felt in his stomach increased as the meaning of the words and righteous indignation of the tone made Harrod draw into himself.

"And I know that there was a Prophecy about Voldemort's return, because I heard a part of it before Headmaster Albus Dumbledore prevented the student body from hearing the rest. The Wizengamot may have quietly ignored the Ministry's blatant violations of our laws for centuries, but it ends now. I am allowed to hear the full prophecy regarding the monster that tried to destroy my family. I am allowed into the Hall of Prophecy by the laws and traditions of Wizarding England set forth by Merlin himself and I will not be denied."

I'm the villain, Harrod thought. He could no longer meet Draco's gaze, which had never wavered from Harrod's eyes. He looked at the floor then saw Draco glance towards the soft footfalls, like a rustling cat.

Draco looked back to Harrod and said, softly. "And I am not alone. Ah, Madam Longbottom," Draco's tone shifted back to the pleasant boy he'd been a moment ago as he turned turning towards a witch who looked like she still belonged in Hogwarts herself, "I do apologize, but I require a second, or perhaps a witness, in order to comply with all these regulations."

Chapter 49: Contingencies

Author's Update - The original version of this chapter had duplicated scenes from Ch. 45. This was a mere oversight on my part, not some clever scheme.

March 6th

"I've already explored this area, Draco," Harry said, as they trudged up another flight of stairs. "We're heading towards the defense lecture hall, but if you go up the eighth flight of stairs you go back to my office. I pass this area every day." Draco nodded, a few steps ahead of Harry.

They'd been walking for a bit, Draco said he had something he wanted to show Harry. A secret room as a reward for Harry showing Draco his office, and this was the rare Saturday afternoon that had nothing scheduled. No Quidditch game, and the N.E.W.T. armies were battling in the streets of Hogsmeade so nothing worth spectating. Harry had considered pulling rank to go watch that battle. During negotiations with the mayor Professor Lockhart had graciously granted the residents permission to stun or harass any annoying students. Harry felt like it would be hysterical. But he'd also wanted to talk with Draco, who seemed pleased to have discovered a secret Harry didn't know. They passed the Barnabas the Barmy tapestry and then Draco veered over to a door that Harry had never noticed.

Draco swung the door opened and bowed dramatically.

"How. About, A nice game. Of Chess?" Draco said with no inflection, no emotion. Harry wandered into the majestic ballroom, the walls were covered with bookshelves, and there were small coffee tables and chairs all around the room, but the center of the ballroom was covered in an elegant eight by eight checkerboard, with chess pieces standing almost as tall as Harry.

Harry Potter chuckled. "You know, if you told me I'd sometimes regret how popular Muggle Movie Night has become, I wouldn't have believed you. Muggle or Wizard?"

Draco dropped his robotic impression, and switched to a formal, fluid voice that Harry called Draco's playwright "By Custom, By Law and by the 2nd ruling of the 18th Wizengamot, the challenged party in the duel gets the right to choose." Draco walked inside the room and the door shut behind him. The torches on the wall were far enough away that the lighting barely flickered, just gave a warm glow, like soft incandescent lighting, only slightly orange.

"You've become quite good at Muggle Chess," Harry said. "You could be great at it."

Now Draco chuckled.

"People like you and me, we'll never get great at chess. We have natural talent and enjoy it, but the effort required is a gigantic waste. So we just spend the rare hour or two playing to relax. And I've found the perfect place, admit it." Draco had taken out both chess sets and placed them on the floor between himself and Harry, who both sat on the ground, cross legged.

"OK, OK. I've got to admit, this place is great. Muggle Chess, then. Wizard chess would hardly be a contest for you, not anymore. Although if these were neutral pieces." Draco walked over to a smaller Wizard Chess set - there were several smaller board scattered around the main board – and took out his wand and waved it at the set "Leviludis!"

The pieces floated up, complaining and scrabbling on the board for purchase. Draco just shushed them quietly, like a gentle mother. Harry watched Draco grabbed two pawns out of mid-air, one white and one black, and put them behind his back, mixing them up. He stuck his hands out, and Harry pointed to Draco's left hand.

Draco opened it to reveal a black pawn. He placed both small pawns on the board. There were two high chairs off to the side of the main board and Draco climbed into the chair slightly on the white side, while Harry climbed into the other on the black side. The small set floated up alongside with Draco, possibly just attached, and he pulled it out of the air and set it down on the table. Draco adjusted his spell so that small board floated, dropping slowly back to the table between them as though it were underwater. Or on the moon.

Draco picked up a small conical megaphone and said "Pawn to Queen Four" and the large pawn down below them slid smoothly two spaces forward. Harry had lent Draco a book, a collection of games from an early tournament to select a challenger for the world championship and Draco had been slowly going over the games with Gregory and Harry in his rare break from studying or (Harry knew), plotting to break into the Hall of Prophecies.

Those games had subtleties they didn't understand, even with the grandmaster commentary, but Draco had picked up a feel for how different opening moves led to different games, and he preferred the more subtle queen pawn openings. Draco passed the megaphone to Harry and he chose his move.

They quickly played the first few moves, passing the megaphone back and forth, and settled into an Old Indian Opening. After Harry's fifth move Draco paused, they'd gotten past a position Draco recognized and could just play from memory.

Draco spent several minutes thinking, but he talked while he thought. It was rude to talk during your opponents turn, so conversations between the two were like extended soliloquies.

"This opening reminds me of a game from your book. Great game. Black sacrificed his queen for only a pawn, but it pulled the white king half way up the board and really exposed him, and then twenty moves later Black won. It's clear, once you play through it, that he hadn't seen the winning position, Black played a few waiting moves just shuffling pieces back and forth, until he saw the winning play. But the sacrifice gave him position and tempo."

Draco exchanged his queen pawn for Harry's king pawn. Harry could retake with either a pawn or a knight. He considered the implications of each move.

"I remember that game. It made an impression on me, too. But with grandmasters you really only get great games when the position is so complicated that neither one of them can see how it ends." Harry recaptured with his pawn. The captured pieces slid gracefully off the board, other pieces moving aside, and then kept going until they were up against one of the walls. You could still see them, if you knew where to look.

"Yeah," said Draco. "If they both agreed that one position was good for one side, the other would naturally avoid that position. So we only witness a great game by the masters when it's nebulous. Most of their excellence is above our heads. It takes a rare position too complicated for even them before we witness fireworks on the board."

"Yes, it's like the Bludger simulation. You avoid a situation where you can lose. If everything goes well with your plan, there's nothing to watch."

Draco and Harry continued to array their pieces as the opening transitioned to midgame, each trying to get more mobility. They challenged each other for the center in a slow build up. During Harry's turn Draco still watched the board spread out below them, but he also took the Wizard chess set beside him and balanced the board on a pawn. It would have been impossible, but the levitation spell made it barely work. The chess pieces complained, and they formed a rough circle around the center of the board to keep it from toppling. It wasn't a regular chess position, pieces were on two squares or more, and all mixed up, but Draco kept tinkering with it.

Harry tried to ignore it and made his move, ordering a pawn forward to storm the kingside. Draco would have counter-attacking possibilities if he exchanged pawns and opened it up, or he could lock the position but be cramped.

Draco flicked the wizard chess set's side at the corner, and the board slowly spun like a top while he thought for several minutes, pausing to flick the wizard board. Beside him, a queen complained loudly about the treatment – calling Draco 'a cretinous cur' – apparently comfortable talking back since Draco was treating that set like a toy, not a game. Draco picked up the megaphone and captured Harry's pawn.

Harry had expected that, neither one of them liked a position where you had few choices, and he'd planned his response but it didn't hurt to double check. The problem with chess is that you had to visualize the position and as you saw further ahead you sometimes misplaced a piece mentally. Some players, probably all the great ones, could see the position perfectly in their head. Harry's visualization wasn't perfect. Harry flicked the wizard chess board a few times then confirmed his analysis and made his move.

Draco nodded. "I see your point about the Bludger," Draco said, "but in real life it probably happens more often." While he was talking Draco reached up and snatched the silver knight off the slowly spinning board. The board lurched wildly, but all of the pieces took a few steps around, shifting their way as they shouted advice to each other. After a minute, the board's wobbling subsided. "After all, in the real world everyone has their own view of the situation. And their own information. If something strange happens, the others compensate."

Draco counter-attacked, as expected. It was a complex position and Harry fell into a deep thought. After a few minutes Draco started spinning the toy between them, poking at pieces with his finger and watching board wobble as the pieces adjusted. Normally it was the right of the person thinking to talk or fidget, so as not to distract the other, but Harry had taken a long time (by their standards) to move, so he didn't press the point.

Harry picked up his megaphone to make his move when suddenly his robes started to constrict and changed color to white. Harry saw Draco flick his wand and say Somnium.

March 7th

Harry heard them coming down the stairs. He was in a basement … somewhere. He didn't recognize it in the hours he'd been awake. Harry grunted as loudly as he could. He was bundled into an Acromantula web, naked except for underwear, trussed tightly onto a cot. His eyes were uncovered, at least. He didn't know how long he'd been awake.

Since Draco stunned him.

He'd used the time to try to figure out what was going on.

The 'how' part didn't take much effort. The robes he'd been wearing were a gift from Draco, and Draco had studied fixed transfiguration. He could switch his own clothes from suit to robes and back. Presumably he'd made one set of robes out of web and had given them to Harry at Christmas. Or switched them out at a later time. Harry might have been able to win a duel with Draco, but being ambushed while in a constricting web, he hadn't had a chance.

A part of Harry admired the elegance of the ambush, while he struggled in the web. But his struggles had merely confirmed that boys his age couldn't fight their way out of strong webs.

Draco had made his move now, but what move?

The real question was 'why?' Slytherin said inside his head.

Had Draco done this as part of an elaborate scheme to test Peverell? Gryffindor offered, but the rest of the voices shouted him down. Well, we can hope, Gryffindor said quietly. But Harry knew it was wishful thinking. It lacked all sense of proportion. Draco might overreach when provoked – he'd done just last year when torturing Harry - but he wouldn't spend ten galleons to win a Knut. Draco hadn't done this out of anger, or fear, or pride. The planning clearly marked this as a plot, or contingency plan, and nothing had changed recently enough to warrant springing the trap.

Nothing you're aware of, anyway, said Ravenclaw.

Had Draco finally decided we're Voldemort? said Hufflepuff.

That risk had always existed, that Draco would reach the wrong conclusion.

No, answer Slytherin. If he had we'd be dead right now. Or worse.

Harry's voices bickered amongst themselves and Harry - or at least, the internal Harry supervisor voice - went off in another direction.

Was this some lesson? Draco and Harry had taught each other lessons, and if so, this would be memorable. As the minutes stretched into hours that seemed less and less likely. Harry's stomach knotted itself. Harry started reaching out from the obvious facts and cast his memory back into the previous semester. The previous summer. Last year. Nothing came up. Perhaps he could ask Draco when he got out, but Harry didn't imagine Draco would be talkative.

If I can even find him. Draco had spent last summer looking for Snape. Harry and Draco had discussed strategies and steps necessary to avoid being discovered. Harry didn't know how long he'd been out, but if Draco didn't want to be found, Harry couldn't find him. The more worrying thought was that if Draco didn't want Harry to be found ... although he had a few contingencies, but they might take a while.

Had Draco discovered Harry's betrayals? That seemed likely. Moody had read Draco's mind under orders, and now Harry regretted not having him dig deeper. If Draco had discovered that fact, although it wasn't at all clear how, he may consider it an act of war.

"And in the real world everyone has their own view of the situation. And their own information." Harry remembered Draco's voice, during the chess game. Had he misjudged Draco so badly? Had Draco misjudged him?

Harry spent his time reviewing everything he knew, and kept coming to the same conclusion. I need more information. I'm missing a fact. He then considered the details about more. Why had Draco used that room to ambush Harry? Well, it would naturally intrigue me. The ambush over the game of chess would appeal to Draco's sense of style, but he'd ignore that if necessary.

Harry had decided that the most likely reason was that the room was out of the way when he heard Gregory's voice shouting from the top of the stairs, "I see him" and Hermione and Gregory raced down the stairs. It took them a while to cut Harry out of the web, he'd lost the sense of time. Harry could see that Hermione had been crying. Gregory's face was set in stone. Just like when he rescued Draco. Hermione blushed when the web finally parted, but Harry just reached up and ripped the webbing off his mouth "What's the situation?"

Hermione said, "We're … not sure. We repelled the attack on Peverell. The chalice is safe. But there's a lot of damage, and not just there, but Hogwarts, too." Harry noticed that her thoughts weren't nearly as organized as usual. He realized the implication right as she said, "At least three Aurors are dead, and some students, too. They think they can save Mad-Eye. I was too late, Harry, I'm sorry ... Draco probably thought he was protecting me but he should have known ... "

"Where's Draco?" Harry asked, and Hermione sucked in her breath and bit her lip.

Gregory shook his head then turned away and went back up the stairs. Harry looked around, he didn't recognize the room. It looked like a small basement apartment, with some goods stored along the walls. There was only a picture, but the picture showed what looked to be a closed cave mouth, rocks jumbled all around the front, perched precariously along the frame. Harry start towards the stairs but stopped. There was a second cot lined up beside the wall and set carefully on top of it was a chess set. A muggle chess set, small, made with light and dark brown wood. All of the pieces were set up in the opening position.

Except both kings had been knocked over.

Hermione stopped biting her lip. "Draco and Neville are dead, Harry."

Author's Note –I had considered a final exam, much like in HPMOR, but honestly I couldn't create a compelling one in any case, Draco's final exam would be composed by Lucius, not Voldemort. You have as much information as Harry (more), but you don't necessarily have all the pieces to fill in all the blanks. But you do have enough information to understand what Draco hoped to achieve. Ignore the tactics, focus on strategy.

A (guest!) reviewer on last chapter mentioned Apollo Robbins, specifically his TED talk and how it applied to attention. That's a good catch, one that Harry would point out, except that Apollo wasn't famous yet. Apollo Robbins is a magician/pickpocket (with at least one published neuropsychology paper co-authorship!) who is an expert on exploiting attention. He likens attention to a security guard watching a row of monitors, but who can only focus on one or two at a time. His TED talk ("The Art of Misdirection") is one of the legitimately brilliant (as compared to "just interesting") lectures I've seen and well worth the ten minutes.

Also, on a related note, I like reviews.

The game discussed was Averbakh-Kotov, Zurich Candidates Tournament, 1953.

Update to the Hot Hand "Fallacy" - The Wall Street Journal had an article saying that Hot Hands actually do exist, courtesy of Adam Sanjuro, Joshua Miller, and some really unintuitive math. FF doesn't like links, but that should be enough to google if you care.

Chapter 50: Thirty-Four Years Later

Author's Note - Based on criticism, it has been suggested that I remove this chapter and repost it later. For now, let me just say that it is entirely skippable. It takes place 34 years later (at the title states), and the next chapter returns to the 'present.' Many readers have complained. For now, I am leaving it. If you do skip it, it should be obvious when you'll need to come back and read it.

Summer had lingered, but by the time that Harry James Pevel crossed the threshold to Platform Nine and Three Quarters fall had arrived. The muggle world felt cool and serene and not at all humid, and the temperature dropped lower still when he crossed the threshold, trailing his children. His youngest - nine with unkempt blonde hair that resisted all attempts at combing with a quiet defiance - broke away from the family while Luna stared at the steam coming from the locomotive engine, entranced and lost in private memory. She recovered, squeezing Harry's hand and then Luna dashed forward calling "Petunia! Petunia!"

Harry had originally taken her name, but Harry James Potter-Evans-Verres-Lovegood had been a mouthful, so he'd simply changed it to Pevel. That contained all the sounds in the right order and also honoured and symbolically linked him with the Peverells, an added bonus. Technically he kept the name Harry Potter, since he was the Lord of the Most Noble and Ancient House of Potter, but that didn't really matter much anymore.

But his biological parents had probably cared, and some factions of wizarding society still placed stock on these things, so Harry sometimes used his formal title, especially during contentious Wizengamot sessions. But most days he was simply Harry Pevel.

Harry looked around the station, at all the children running back and forth, gossiping, hugging, trading stories of their summer vacation, and otherwise acting like children. Well, like normal children, anyway. After his first year he'd stopped coming early to the train rides, because the pressure of being The Boy Who LIved made it an exhausting experience, although he would always remember the first train ride and meeting Hermione. After his second year, Harry couldn't afford to waste a full day going to and from Hogwarts each semester, and had simply skipped the trips completely. He'd never been one to enjoy crowds of people, in any case.

A familiar couple waved and Harry waved back. Harry's middle son called out to them. "Hi Aunt Hermione! Uncle Ron!" Michael ran off and hugged his aunt, then went to play with young Draco Weasley. Harry started to head over to them, quietly flanked by Mr. Goyle and Mr. Crabbe. Harry could ignore the rest of the parents on the platform, confident that they were scanning the crowd for threats. Gregory had argued against a public appearance, but Harry had overruled them. Correction, said Ravenclaw, Gregory acquiesced.

Harry hadn't been physically attacked in nearly two decades. They still worried. In many ways they still blamed themselves for not seeing the attacks coming in the first place, even though there had been no earthly way for them to know, during the early years.

Harry looked down at his oldest, who had trailed along beside him. "Why don't you join the other children?" Harry didn't hide the pang he felt letting him go off, even thought it was only to Hogwarts.

Harry had scheduled Albus for the first train. Hogwarts required two trains now, class sizes being so much larger. Harry could have taken him personally, but wouldn't dream of denying his son the full experience of the Hogwarts he loved. Albus had asked why they needed a train to get to Dad's office and Harry had started to explain, but had just shrugged.

"What if they don't think I'm smart, Dad? What if they don't put me in Ravenclaw?" Albus said, with the slightest hint of desperation in his voice.

Harry crouched down so that he was looking up at his son and stared at his beautiful blue eyes. "Why are you worried about that?" Harry's long white beard touched the ground. At first, the beard had started as an affectation, just playing the part for the country of the wise old wizard he'd hoped to become someday. Now, it seemed natural, and he rarely thought about it, but he instinctively scooped it up off the concrete. Albus met his eyes, and Harry saw the worry.

"Because … because! I'm not you, Dad! Everyone says you're the most clever, that you invented cleverness, and they'll expect me to... you know." Albus hyperventilated slightly, before getting his breathing under control. "I can't live up to it..."

"You, Albus Quirinus Pevel are named after two great men. Quirinius Quirrel made Offense against the Dark Arts what it is today. He was a Slytherin. And Albus Dumbledore had both my jobs and did them both better. And he was a Gryffindor."

Albus gulped a breath. "A Gryffindor? Really? But they ..." He stopped.

Harry shook his head. "The houses show your most dominant trait, or the one you must wish to improve. But no person can be reduced to a single adjective. The houses are only a shorthand, and then are great wizards and witches in every house. Remember what I say. If I can see farther than those who came before me..."

"It's only because I stand on the shoulders of giants. Not literal ones. Figurative." Albus said, finishing the quote. He hugged his father and ran after his mother to say goodbye.

Hermione walked over, looking completely normal, although she'd cut her hair short over the summer, Harry noted. She'd managed to completely hide her glamour and had even gone so far as to adjust her appearance to look ... mundane. But even before she'd deglamoured with her self-invented potion (the final ingredient was a claw from a Blast-ended Skrewt) the Girl-Who-Revived didn't draw much attention these days. Hermione rarely did anything dangerous and - as far as the public knew - hadn't done anything important in fifteen years. If you'd seen her as a teenager, like Harry had, you'd have imagined her as a a movie star by the time she grew up. In actuality, she didn't stand out or turn heads, and that was mostly by design. She'd had enough with well wishers and followers by the time they'd turned twenty.

Harry didn't really see the woman standing in front of him as she was. In his mind, she was always a teenager. He knew that was a flaw, but it was one he preferred to live with.

Harry had known instantly that Draco's Diary, not his Letter, was the final gambit. Draco's way of ensuring Hermione Granger helped Harry Potter, but always at arm's length. At a distance. As a friend. When he'd finally gotten up his courage and asked her on a date, Hermione agreed they could be more without risking the world. But we never will be, she'd said. If Draco had been around, one of them would have ended up with Hermione. But with Draco gone...

Harry reminded Hermione too much of those they'd lost. He could move past it, but Hermione hadn't. She felt much more deeply than he did, a side effect of his coldness. Harry experienced great joy and great loss and felt pain for the damage he'd done. He knew about countless millions he hadn't saved, but lingering on it wasn't useful and didn't help them. Harry planned as carefully as he could, but emotionally lived in each movement, then moved on. At least, he usually did, but seeing Hermione reminded him of his regrets. And he knew the same was true for her.

My joys and pain echo constantly, she'd said all those years ago. By way of apology.

Harry never understood what she saw in Ron.

After the hugs and handshakes Hermione pulled Harry aside and whispered "I think we should delay repealing the Statute."

Harry Pevel sighed internally then put on his finest wise face, his Albus Dumbledore #2, "We've been over this. If we miss this Convocation, we'll have to wait five years for the next one."

"We are immortal, Harry. There's no rush."

"People will die." Harry didn't cry, not any more, when considering the price his caution had cost. They both knew he felt it, that the disapproval in his voice was real. "What reason do you have?"

"It's Xare, he's looking a bit peaky. I don't think he'll be available, should a problem arise. I'll have limited tactical mobility with all the warding going on." Harry could sense Gregory, just two feet behind him, dividing his attention. Vincent hadn't stopped scanning the crowd, but this was now a security matter and so now they were splitting duties and paying attention to Harry's conversation, since it was no longer just politics. Gregory and Vincent would discuss it amongst themselves, later. They might even ask my opinion, Harry thought.

"Who would attack us, Hermione? I think we've run out of Dark Wizards."

Hermione interrupted. "Sethra Lavode..."

Harry inter-re-upted. "Yes, she lives; but stuck in her mountain for a few hundred years. After that? I think she'll be impressed."

"Harry, doesn't it seem, I don't know, convenient? How everything is working, how the opposition has melted away, to finally be unified after all of that political maneuvering. All the obstacles, all the delays."

Harry considered it.

"No, it doesn't. We spent decades arranging this. How much pain did you go through, dying all those times? How often did we have to prove, time and again, that I wasn't Voldemort. How many did I fail to save? How many shadows we jumped at, just to make sure there was no threat. Now - finally! - we're gaining numbers. We aren't alone. We've pushed the rationality of graduating classes at least one standard deviation to the right. This generation is firmly behind us, they've moved the needle! Albus fears he's not smart enough! Not smart enough, Hermione. And you know he'd have done well, been a General by 3rd year, back in the day."

Harry looked down. "Now he's just an average wizard boy."

Harry saw that Hermione knew how much it hurt him to admit that. He hoped she knew how much wisdom he'd gained over the last decade. Draco had been right in this, that for too long Harry's strength had been its own corresponding weakness. Now having his own family had provided balance and given Harry a lot of practical insight into how other people reacted to him. Draco came so close to being right about everything. Harry realized he'd drifted into thought and refocused on Hermione, as the prefects starting herding the first years onto the train.

"No, Hermione, it does not appear convenient to me at all. And once I finish this task, I will have time to rescue Dumbledore, and beg his forgiveness."

"The last part is irrelevant, and you know it..."

Harry Potter shrugged, conceding the point, but Hermione knew what he'd meant. By unspoken agreement, they agreed to let work wait until family was gone and the rushed around the station, hugging kids and greeting old friends. They'd save their strategizing and politicking for a few hours, once they were back at the office. They'd saved most of the Wizarding world.

Soon, they'd save everyone else.

All was well.

Author's Note - If you read the previous chapter during the first day it was posted, two sections were (near) duplicates of part of Chapter 45 and have been removed. There was no grand plan on that, it was just an oversight.

And yes, I'm going to go back to the 'present' in the next chapter. (I'm not a monster).

Chapter 52: Fully Awake

Excerpts from on-scene depositions taken immediately after the attack on Peverell Hospital on the morning of March 7th, 1993. Recorded by TrueQuill(tm).

Igor Karkaroff (3 drops Vs) - "Right when we came in some Auror threw the Chalice and told us to take it and go, just not to hurt the patients. I killed him and continued with the assault. It was an obvious distraction. Aurors that well armed doesn't just give up right away, even in a hostage situation. No, Lockhart didn't tell me the Chalice was a fake before. Honestly, it's an insulting plan."

.

Auror Alexander Williams (1 drop Vs) - "And then he went flying past me, casting Auror grade spells! I knew he'd been unconscious earlier, but that Malfoy boy was awake and fighting like a demon. Totally fearless. I can't understand it. No, I wasn't Confounded, I'm telling you..."

.

Phillip Cerci (3 drops Vs) - "...well, we saw Malfoy's body on the way in, the Auror's probably dropped him in the initial attack. We took up a defensive position against the hallway to Hogwarts, there were professors behind us right away. No idea how they caught us. Adolphus said your backups were crossing the wards into Hogwarts, so we had to defend to give the others time to take the Chalice so it was busy. I was right next to Selwyn and Septavia got killed early in the cross fire, and damned if not a few minutes later Malfoy charges in, cusses out Selwyn. Actually cusses him out. Selwyn's killed for less, but the boy probably thought it was Igor and he's screaming about how we screwed up and searching for Septavia's wand, then he disappeared to help get the Stone, and several minutes later it came flying out, and I thought we'd done it..."

.

Auror 'Mike' Li (1 drop Vs) - "...I thought we were dead when the Fiendfyre started. Backup instantly cut off and the walls were melting. I'd followed protocol, but after another minute we're out gunned, Bahry's dead, and I'm cut off from everyone else. Just me, a few patients, and the unconscious Malfoy. Someone, maybe Prabat, had moved the civilians away from the Fiendfyre. I thought I was dead. Ennervating Malfoy saved my life. "

.

Igor Karkaroff (3 drop Vs) - "Why did we fail? We lost the element of surprise and our plan fell apart, and it was chaos. We almost pulled it off anyway. If he [Draco Malfoy] hadn't died, we might have..."

.

Hermione Granger (1 drop Vs) - "Because he was Impieriused! I don't know who did it. A professor obviously, Hogwart's has wards. Draco wouldn't help them. I've heard the other Aurors, Draco fought against the attack."

Interrogator - How do you explain the fact that Draco went through the Thief's Downfall, which ends any Imperius and then did not raise the alarm and spent 10 minutes scouting the hospital.

Hermione Granger (1 drop Vs) - "I can't. I need to go find Harry. I've given my statement. Let go of me, this is important. (Shouting): Headmistress! ... I'll ... don't ... let go! Now!"

Interrogator - "[Redacted, incivility related]! (gasping) Stop her! Stop her!"

[End Transcript]

Harry Potter opened his eyes and stared blankly up at the ceiling. The dark world came into focus, the only light a fiery chicken-like head staring down at him. The phoenix crooned softly, wings spread wide as if to shield the boy below him from the flaws of the world dropping on him like rain.

"Fawkes," Harry croaked, "Where were you on the morning of March 7th?"

Fawkes looked at him, twisting his head quizzically from side to side, all the while singing.

"Good Morning, Mr. Potter." Harry glanced around. It was night time in the Hogwarts infirmary. He didn't see anyone else around, although several of the nearby beds were occupied. The closest was occupied by a rather large body, as far as Harry could tell. An adult, face hidden under blankets. Harry pulled himself up into a sitting position, and stared at the man sitting in a small wooden chair beside his bed.

"Professor Asimov, what day is it? Why are you here?"

"It's the morning of the thirteenth. Almost five in the morning. I was keeping your father company, but Madam Pomfrey slipped him something in his water to help him sleep. I suspect if he hadn't taken it they'd have done something more ... drastic. You aren't allowed non-family visitors, really, but they allowed me as a guest of your parents, since I'm mostly harmless."

Harry nodded. After a second ambush you didn't have to be Mad-Eye Moody to restrict access, and a squib professor was a safe bedside companion. Particularly if you had Fawkes to raise the alarm if he tried to smother you with a pillow. Harry noticed a folded newspaper sticking out from underneath Professor Asimov's chair. There was a glass of water on the bedside table and Harry drank it greedily.

"Can I read that, Professor?" Harry said, pointing to the newspaper.

"I had to sneak this in, you know. They don't want your parents to know anything and I think they're more than a touch worried about what you'll do when you see it." While he spoke Professor Asimov took the folded up newspaper and handed it over. "Still, now that I've talked to your Father I can guess that it was you who got me this job. And saved my life. The Headmistress wouldn't have had the faintest clue who I am, would she?"

Harry snatched the paper. "So, Dad talked your ear off, did he?"

"Well, he didn't have anyone else to talk to, but yes, he did. He said very flattering things, but of course he's a Professor - a real one - and I'm just an author who got rescued by magicians, so he could tell me some interesting stories..."

While Professor Asimov kept talking Harry scanned yesterday's copy of the Daily Prophet. There were editorials accusing him of being Voldemort. He'd expected that, Draco's plan had crystallized in his head the instant he'd seen the image of Fred and George's map projected for all of Slytherin House (and Narcissa Malfoy) to see. Surprisingly there were a number of more moderate editorials, saying that even if Harry Potter was a soul-copy, the fault rested with the government officials who 'aided and abetted him,' and had proven themselves untrustworthy because of their lack of due diligence. These editorials referred to the prior Daily Prophet's stunning expose on Harry Potter's influence on Hogwarts and the Ministry.

There were calls for investigations and further demands to open the Hall of Prophecy once and for all to resolve this.

Draco, or his accomplices, had set up a debate with two sides:

EITHER Harry Potter was Voldemort and should be killed OR Harry Potter probably wasn't actually Voldemort, but just to be safe should be kept well away from the halls of power, and anyone who had ever helped him should be stripped of all titles.

Draco framed the debate so that even actual innocence implies guilt, Harry's inner Slytherin whistled appreciatively. He's arguing that they should have known you were a risk and kept you at arms length. After a second Harry realized that both of his inner voices were assuming Draco was still alive, but the probability of that had ... well, not drastically increased. But gone up.

The attack had been well planned. Narcissa Malfoy had recognized the name Tom Riddle. Of course she shouldn't have trusted the information, said Ravenclaw.

But she was in a foul state of mind, no doubt, said Hufflepuff.

Most importantly, there were a bunch of witnesses who probably didn't even register what they'd seen, and almost certainly had not registered it's import. Perhaps someone had noted that the Maurader's Map displayed everyone's name right but Harry, but they'd probably been looking at Harry dying, or Vincent and Crabbe attacking Professor Slughorn, or later on at Narcissa raging. They probably saw the name Tom Riddle, but it didn't register. And in any case the map display was used for simulations. Why, it routinely generated lies.

It would never occur to an Auror to obliviate or memory charm the students, and the information needed to determine it was necessary wouldn't have made it up the chain. There were ways it could have been prevented, but Slughorn - as the attacker - could have countermeasures.

Judging from the Daily Prophet, he'd had them in place. There was a lengthy article on all that was publicly known about Tom Riddle, and comparing those facts with what was known about Harry Potter. There weren't many details of the attack. That made sense, the news of his attack came out in the prior edition. These were reaction pieces.

"What happened ... after I passed out?"

"Well, they arrested Horace of course. Put him in Gilderoy's cell, I'm told. Lady Malfoy smashed the place up pretty well, but they let her go."

"But she...," Harry started to say she attacked me. But he'd passed out, he didn't know what she'd done. It certainly looked like she was about to attack Harry. Or perhaps Xare or Hermione.

Professor Asimov looked down, abashed. "Augusta vouched for her. Threw a fit. Said that she'd have attacked you herself if she'd been there and seen what Narcissa saw."

Harry considered. A grieving widow, straight after her only son's funeral, just seeing compelling evidence that the butcher who murdered her son and her husband was alive. A crime, yes, but hardly pre-meditated. Assuming that she was actually surprised by the news. Any competent lawyer could keep Narcissa out of jail in a muggle court, at least pending the trial. Mix in wizard politics and it made sense that Amelia Bones released her, lacking a smoking gun. Which wouldn't exist if Narcissa were actually surprised, and certainly wouldn't if she wasn't.

Harry nodded, then folded the newspaper up and dropped it onto his sheets. There were no funeral announcements, and Professor Asimov hadn't said anything, but he needed to check.

"Did anyone die? When I was poisoned?"

"Thankfully not."

Harry spent several moments considering the latest attack on him. Coupled with the newspaper articles it had been revealing. Now Draco's motive was clear. Pieces started clicking into place, first slowly but with growing speed. Harry spent a few minutes thinking, and listening to Fawkes quiet song, before speaking again.

"You don't seem to have any problem with me," Harry said.

"We haven't talked much," Professor Asimov said. In fact, Harry had avoided talking to him, mostly to avoid acting like a starry eyed fan or stupid kid. But also because he didn't want to contaminate the lessons on Muggle Studies, or influence Professor Asimov's views on how to convert magical society to a more rational way of thinking.

So he'd stayed away.

"Draco spoke well of you, a few times. Talking to the other professors and the Headmistress was different. You ... bewilder them. But they're just witches and wizards, and I'm a Science Fiction author. I've seen boys like you for decades. Maybe not quite so smart. But hundreds of dreamers, the ones who just don't fit in. To your teachers, Harry Potter is a mystery. To me, well, I've run into him before. And just now, over the last day, I've spoken to your father, and the stories he tells me reminds me of a Richard Feynman."

"I remind you of Richard Feynman?" Harry asked, with unrestrained glee.

"Not in science, although I gather you are well advanced, but in the mindset, attacking problems from unexpected angles. Novel solutions. And, I must admit, your talent for self-promotion. You both leave a trail of amazing stories in your wake as a calling card. But yes, like Feynman. And then I started to think about what possible use you could have for an old writer such as myself, and the only thought I could come up with was that you wanted me as your library and viewed yourself as more Hari Seldon than Harry Potter. Am I right?"

"It sounds kind of arrogant when you put it that way," Harry grumbled.

"Oh, it is arrogant! But Seldon was striving to save the universe, and I see before me a small boy who read my book, and dreamed of saving the universe one day, and then found himself with just that option. How could I possibly think you are evil?"

They shared a laugh, but then Professor Asimov frowned. "But, several of my colleagues who are much more knowledgeable than I am do consider you evil, and at least one tried to murder you. And I can't quite figure out what Draco was planning, but he certainly felt that drastic measures were necessary for some reason, although he never told me why. Come to think of it, one of the first things he did was to warn me that I shouldn't mistake Hogwarts students for normal children, and that what I thought of as games were deadly serious. At the time I just humoured him."

"When was this?"

"The first day of classes."

Harry thought back to the train ride at the beginning of the year, how Draco had said he'd wanted an introduction to Professor Asimov. The sun had started to rise, and the first wisps of daylight streamed in through the window. Madam Pomfrey came by on her rounds and examined Harry for a few minutes, then declared that he still needed to rest. Harry asked her about the poison, but she just frowned and shushed him, said that his prognosis was fine, and told Professor Asimov in no uncertain terms that Harry was not to be pestered. Professor Asimov got up to leave, but as he was walking out he turned back, ignoring Madam Pomfrey's complaint.

"When you do figure this out, you'll explain it to me, won't you?" Professor Asimov's voice had the slightest hint of pleading.

"I promise. Soon. Once they release me, I need to do something, but then..."

Harry nodded as Madam Pomfrey shoved Professor Asimov out the door, while casting Somnium at the small boy with the lightning scar under her care.

8pm

Harry walked around the room, amazed at the differences. The walls were scorched and melted, and the floor wasn't flat - it warped up and down as you moved from the front to the back, as though the heat had caused the marble itself to start bubbling like pancake batter, and it had frozen in place when the heat had been removed. The walls weren't just scorched black, but purple and green and a few colours Harry didn't have words for. For a moment Harry ignored the people around him, enthralled in the power demonstrated by the damage. He ignored Hermione and Professor Asimov's questions, not even really hearing them at some level. Harry only woke up when he heard Amelia Bones quiet voice come through the door.

"And Minerva, I've got Ministers screaming at me, the Wizengamot is in a snit. Rumours of centaurs barricading themselves in caves to avoid having to look at the sky, Poland is demanding that we move the Chalice somewhere safe, Goblins are sending a delegation for some reason, and don't even get me started on the Americans, why the Salem Institute of Witches..." she stopped abruptly when she realized that the room had more than just Harry Potter.

"Mr. Potter," said Headmistress McGonagall, walking beside Madam Bones. "Ah, good evening, Professor Asimov. Miss Granger."

"Headmistress, Chief Warlock. I've got some answers, not everything but I know you're under considerable political pressure, so I thought I'd walk you through the main points. Then you can hold a press conference or call a special session of the Wizengamot, as you see fit."

Amelia Bones nodded, but there was a frown on her face. "I can hardly complain about the Girl-Who-Revived being here, she was a witness. And frankly people love her. But I protest Professor Asimov's presence. He's not even a wizard, and I don't see why he's here."

"Amaneunsis," Harry said automatically, then hastily explained "Not in the strict sense of being a note taker, more of in the literary sense that he's my ... living memory, if you will. Call him my conscience for this matter. He has an outsider's view, and is naturally sympathetic towards Lockhart and Slughorn, and Draco and Neville for that matter. Not to mention he has a good grasp on the general sweep of history, without being influenced by the specific history of Magical England, which I think might bias our decisions. We have to decide how we respond to the Daily Prophet's attacks, and I think he'll have good advice. Oh, and I promised him. Anyway, after this is done I'll go interview the Professor Slughorn, just to wrap up loose ends that don't affect the pressing political matters..."

"If you haven't interviewed him, how can you be sure your story is right," said the Headmistress, as she cocked her head inquisitively. Harry smiled at the question.

"A great question, Headmistress. I've interviewed some perpetrators and the surviving Aurors, and read the remaining transcripts of Mad-Eye's interrogations. I caught up on those I missed this morning. That includes Lockhart's interview under Veritaserum and Slughorn's initial statement after the attack. There are questions I need answered, but those statements of fact seem thorough. The timeline isn't complete, but I don't think the gaps matter. Well, not immediately. And Auror Li's interview carries particular weight. I just finished conducting a follow on. There's a lot going on, but it is just a battle. We do after action reports all the time."

"Alastor shouldn't be investigating right now," said Amelia Bones, but there was resignation in her voice. "I'd take over the investigation, but it would imply a lack of faith in Thicknesse. I do miss the simplicity of the DMLE. But Mad Eye should leave that to the Aurors and recover."

"If you wanted to control him, you shouldn't have let him retire. Actually, now that we have the ... Chalice, it seems to me that mandatory retirement should be revisited," Harry said, "But I digress. It's a simple plot, really, because the attempted heist was a feint."

"A feint?" said Madam Bones, her voice rising and shooting glances around the room. Hermione was nodding along, and Professor Asimov was just following the proceedings quietly. McGonagall's jaw had dropped slightly, but she quickly recovered and shut it tightly.

"Twenty dark wizards attack Hogwarts and Peverell and invest Merlin knows how many Galleons for a feint? I could understand the attack for the Chalice, it holds the key to life itself."

"Yes, and we grossly underestimated the probability of a serious brute force attack, which is what Mad-Eye is currently fixing, Madam Bones."

Harry pondered. We'd need a whole compound, not just a small annex. Harry remembered the old saying: Brute force attack failed? Needs more brute force.

"I'll admit," offered Amelia Bones, "that the timing of the second attack is suspicious, and may not just be a coincidence..."

"It's not unreasonable to look at Slughorn's attack as just taking advantage of the timing," Harry said. "And as far as the wizards in custody know, they aren't related. For them, the goal was the Chalice. And they would have gotten away with too, if it weren't for those meddling kids."

Harry smiled at the last one and Professor Asimov chuckled, but Hermione just shook her head so Harry sighed and continued. Explaining the joke never helped.

"No," Harry said, "the attackers were duped by their inside man, Draco Malfoy." Before anyone could interrupt he tossed the copy of the Daily Prophet on the floor.

"One of Lucius's old rules. Look at the results and see who profits. As a heist, this was a bust. But as a way of exposing me? Resounding success. This entire thing was an experiment and, judging from the editorials in today's paper, an ongoing experiment. But back up and consider, Madam Bones, how you reacted when you found out I defeated Voldemort and was Dumbledore's heir as a mere child. Then contemplate how you felt when you found out I was, in some ways, a copy of Voldemort's soul."

"I thought I took it well," she sniffed.

"Draco found all of that by the end of the first day of school, after suffering the trauma of losing his father. He's suspected me of being Voldemort for a while, I knew that, and struggled for a way to resolve it. It's a difficult problem, with no great solution ... I actually discussed this with Quirrel last year. Anyway, for Draco it wouldn't be enough to discover whether I was Voldemort. If he did that I'd kill him. I mean, if I was actually evil. Draco needed to neutralize me until the results of the experiment came in. And he wanted to ensure that if I was Voldemort." Here Harry trailed off for a second, before continuing, "that if I actually was Voldemort and killed Draco, it wouldn't help. Draco needed to expose me to a wide audience."

"The heist set pieces in place for his real experiment, a grand misdirection. I couldn't figure it out before the second attack, because I was working under the theory that Peverell was the target, which didn't make sense with the facts at hand. But with the new motive, everything makes sense. Now I'm revealed as Tom Riddle, which is Voldemort as far as Draco is concerned. And the Prophet has published the information that Voldemort was Tom Riddle. He's spread that information far and wide. Draco is trying to isolate me, and making sure that everyone with a grudge against Voldemort knows it."

"He couldn't bring himself to kill you before," Hermione muttered. "Because he might be wrong."

"Right."

"Draco survived?" said Professor Asimov.

"That's ... complicated. Maybe. I'm still checking. For now, consider 'Draco' to be a conspiracy, instead of a person. At least after the attack. This gets confusing. But before the attack, Draco - the real Draco - wanted to determine if I'm Voldemort. So, an experiment. He knew he wouldn't get many volunteers by saying 'Hey, do you want to hunt down another potential Voldemort?' Too much risk and not enough reward. But dangling the Chalice in front of greedy Wizards? Well, that recruited an army."

"I can hardly be accused of being a supporter of House Malfoy," said the Headmistress in her prim accent, "but I refuse to believe that Draco Malfoy would do something so ... evil."

"I agree, Draco had resolve but willfully endangering so many lives..." said Professor Asimov.

"I don't think he did," said Harry quietly. "But I have some facts you don't. First, I invited Draco at the beginning of the year to help me test the security, so he was well placed to judge how effective the attack would be. Second, Peverell would have been attacked in any case, I had even mentioned that there were groups of Dark Wizards already planning on attacking. Aurors were already in danger. Draco just shifted their timetable. And finally, by all accounts Draco tried to make the attack more subtle, less lethal."

"But they came through Hogwarts," countered Madam Bones, who had also read the transcripts. "What if they'd stumbled on a student...aah, the wards."

"Right. In the letters from their inside man, they were warned time and again about the Hogwarts wards. They couldn't hurt a student, they'd be limited to harmless spells until after they broke into Peverell. They just Somniumed anyone they stumbled across and hid the bodies. And they knew that only a Professor could Imperius or memory alter a student, so they wouldn't be tempted. Any attack on a student would mean discovery and failure. One letter rather credulously mentioned a legend that the very statues of Hogwarts would exact vengeance on outsiders who threatened a student. No, Draco's plan took measures to move risk away from the innocent."

"Not enough measures, apparently," said Professor Asimov. "Or did one of them simply forget?"

"Walk us through it," said Madam Bones, firmly.

Harry gestured to the room around them.

"The attack starts here. And ends here, I suppose. There's some speculation involved, and I've filled in a few gaps, but most of this is straight from the transcripts. A few details to iron out, but the broad strokes are right. So, on the afternoon of March 6th Draco lured me here and then ambushed me and smuggled me out of Hogwarts..."

"But there's no way out," said Hermione.

"Not anymore," Harry agreed. "This room ... has a power. I don't really understand it yet, but I suspect it's gone. Not much works after getting hit with Fiendfyre. Sometime after I got knocked out, Draco created a tunnel to Hogsmeade from here. Later they burned this room. Also part of their plan, to cover their tracks when they escaped. Anyway, after Draco stunned me ..."

Chapter 56: Bluff and Double Bluff, Pt 4

Gilderoy Lockhart poked his head around the corner, then rapidly pulled it back. He dropped to the ground as spells blazed through the now-empty doorway. Lockhart cautiously raised himself back to a crawl and shuffled back a pace or two.

"I count five of them," he said. "A praesidium spell as their major defense, beyond that they are just using the beds for cover."

Auror Frank Wellington, a tall wiry man, with energy like someone had captured a lightning bolt and frozen it in place, shook his head. "Those bed frames are enchanted, too. Not totally impenetrable, but they'll stop most things."

Professor Flitwick let out an exasperated sigh, which came out as a mid-pitch squeak. Wellington just shrugged his shoulders. "It's meant to be a defensible position."

Flitwick, Lockhart and the three Aurors conferred. The Praesidium would block any spell moving too quickly, but a slow spell could get through. It also didn't stop anything physical.

The small-ish Auror, whose name Gilderoy had forgotten, said "The only real option is to charge, and we'd be sitting ducks. The rest of the squads are coming into from the back, we'll have numbers shortly."

"Listen, Todd," said Christine, the third Auror, "You know what they say about the job, two years of boredom for two minutes of terror. I didn't sign up to miss out on my two minutes."

Gilderoy chuckled. He did know Christine - they'd been in Ravenclaw together. Their months together weren't boring. And they'd had at least five minutes of terror of being discovered. She'd been a firecracker as a young woman, and that hadn't changed. Still...Gilderoy agreed with Todd. He was about to raise the point when there was a rustling from the hallway behind him and he spun, quickly adjusting his custodiet shield to protect against an ambush. Theoretically there were only Hogwarts professors and Aurors behind him, but ...

Gilderoy Lockhart stopped mid-spell as Hermione Granger skidded to a halt.

"General Granger," Gilderoy said, still wearing the smile he'd had from his earlier reminiscing.

"Go away, Miss," said Frank, "This isn't the place for students."

"Polyjuice," whispered Flitwick quietly, reminding everyone. Hermione had her hands up, but gave no sign of leaving.

"I can help, Professor, I can!" She didn't plead. Hermione Granger seems twice her age. Either its not her or this is personal, Gilderoy thought.

"Tell me something only Hermione Granger would know."

"Uh, during Christmas Break we ran into each other at The Tragedy of Light and Narcissa was mad at Draco and tried to insult me with some floriography, so I just ..."

"Anyone could have read about that in the gossip sheets, Miss Granger," Professor Lockhart said.

"They printed that?" Hermione gasped in a voice squeakier than Flitwick's, before turning bright red..

"...but no imposter would use that particular phrasing. Or blush so much," Gilderoy finished as he lowered his wand, nodding to the scowling Aurors. Hermione ran over. Professor Flitwick stood in her way, preventing her from advancing any further towards the door, face stern.

"Listen, Lockhart," said Christine, and the use of his last name grabbed his attention, "we're in charge and I'm not going to let a student..."

Gilderoy shushed her and waved his hand, then bent down and huddled next to Hermione, "We need to outflank them. Miss Granger, can your Phoenix move us into position? There are wards around Peverell, but it's possible to move inside those wards, if not through them. If we step one foot in..."

"They trapped him!" she started to describe what had happened, but Gilderoy stopped listening and after a few more words Hermione Granger collapsed from his wordless Somnium. He caught her gently.

"Seriously, Christine," Gilderoy shook his head, "Do you really think I'd let a second year charge into battle? I'll drag her back to safety. Horace should have has stock of potions back in the staging area, and I think some explosive draughts and caligo noctus should work nicely."

Gilderoy Lockhart easily picked up the limp form of Hermione Granger, glancing at the wand still clasped in her hand. "And I'll give Pomona her wand back. What have you been up to, Miss Granger?" he chuckled.

"Bring along some House Elves," said Frank, "in case they get desperate and start flinging killing curses."

Gilderoy nodded as he rushed back towards the infirmary.

Selwyn's vision dropped out instantly as black smoke flooded into the room. He'd seen the fragile flasks as they'd arced to various corners of the room and shouted out a warning. Selwyn kept his left hand on the robed figure next to him, so that he could tell if she got hit or move away, while he counted in his head eins zwei drei. Selwyn fired off several spells at the doorway. The room exploded with noise, a weaponized Sonorus spell that Aurors world-wide used to intimidate crowds. They'd prepared for that, of course. His shields automatically muted any dangerously loud sounds, but still allow him to hear as the footsteps moved. The witch next to him was spraying area effect curses to the left of the doorway and Selwyn heard a shield crackling, so he shifted and fired to the left. Already the fog was disappearing, it would be gone soon.

"They are through," he cried out in German. They wouldn't release the fog until they were all in. "Fall back while we have cover!" Selwyn got up, turned and ran, careful to jump over the corpse he knew was beside him. He easily jumped, but his legs felt strangely numb and seemed sluggish. When he landed his right leg wasn't positioned properly and gave out from under him. Selwyn raised his arms to protect his face from the impact of landing, but his right arm moved a bit sluggishly and he cracked his face against the floor.

Selwyn looked down at his leg and he could see that he'd broken his right leg when he'd landed. That should hurt he thought, as he tried to scramble up, but his motions were like trying to swim in a pool of syrup, slow and awkward. The fog had cleared and he was out in the open and Selywn tried to drag himself away as he could hear them screaming for him to get up.

But no spell hit me was Selwyn's final thought as the Aurors closed in and fired slow moving draining spells.

"Draco!" Gilderoy's face edged towards a smile, then quickly turned to a frown as he strode towards his student, who stood poking one of the blood red stones on the floor with his cane to move it into the pile of known fakes. By now word of the Midas curse had spread.

Gilderoy continued "What are you doing here, Draco?"

The Aurors were busy securing the remaining prisoners, carefully avoiding the other seven or eight red stones scattered around the room. Draco turned and looked at him for a second, confusion on his face. Draco knows everyone, Gilderoy thought as he screamed out "Imposter!" and raised his wand. The surrounding Aurors - adrenaline still fresh and flowing through their systems - all shifted wands, about to fire at somebody, anybody, as 'Draco' dove behind the nearest bed.

"Orion Elbow Purple," screamed 'Draco.' "Orion Elbow Purple!"

Gilderoy's spell streaked through the air where 'Draco' had stood while a rush of Aurors lowered their wands, shouting that Draco was an Auror.

Gilderoy noted several Aurors aimed wands on him, though at least one still had 'Draco' in his sights.

He spoke slowly and deliberately. "That is not Draco."

"I'm Auror Mike Li," came Draco's voice. "The password of the day is Orion Elbow Purple! The Aurors in the room are Frank Wellington, Aleister Seville, uh..." Draco's head poked over the bed as he glanced around the room, "Christine King is just walking into the room. I don't know you, the tall one, but you don't work in Peverell..."

The tall one said "Nicodemus Salamander."

Gilderoy's wand stayed up. "Attackers Polyjuiced as students," he said, voice unsure.

"And Professors," said one of the Aurors. Gilderoy lowered his wand. "I suppose we just need to keep each other in sight for the next few hours until it wears off. Or doesn't, in my case."

As they sized each other up, Christine walked over and said. "I'll vouch for him, we went to school together. This is Professor Lockhart. Gilderoy. I found Draco ... he's in the other room."

Gilderoy looked at her. "I'm sorry," she said, face ashen. Gilderoy Lockhart ran into the other room.

Draco Malfoy was sprawled face up on the ground with a surprised look etched on his face. His cane was still in his hand. As soon as he saw it, Gilderoy spun on the following 'Draco,' who had his hands up in surrender. "How is it that..."

"He gave me a copy of his cane during the attack," Mike Li said, but already his form was bubbling and growing to full size, and Gilderoy could see in the corner of his eyes that the other Aurors recognized the former Draco. "He'd been doing a security test, he just happened to be here during the attack..." As the Auror continued speaking he stretched out and grew, skin and hair darkening as he reverted back to his true form, and Gilderoy's hand dropped, wand drooping almost to the ground.

"I was supposed to protect him," Lockhart said morosely.

A sly chuckle came from a bound figure lying on the ground, a blonde witch with splotchy complexion. Two Aurors were still securing her. "He'd have died in any case, once he'd finished betraying you..." she laughed.

Gilderoy's eyes narrowed and his wand barely had to move at all as he hissed out the word Crucio.

The witch's scream pierced through the room for thirty seconds before the Aurors broke through Lockhart's shields.

Harry sat back in his chair, throat sore. Amelia Bones and Headmistress McGonagall exchanged a glance. Professor Asimov, who had been staring at the ceiling, returned his gaze to the assembled crowd.

"Anyway," Harry said, "That's pretty much the end. They found Draco's body next to the real Philosopher's Stone, and what with all the Midnight Fog and the chaos of battle, it's an open question if that body belongs to Draco, or he managed to grab the stone and permanently PolyJuice into someone else's form and that body is someone we assumed burned to death in the Fiendfyre."

Harry waited for crosstalk and challenges that never came. Hermione's face, set like granite, gave no indication of any emotion. Harry knew Professor Asimov wouldn't volunteer any suggestion, although he had expected more questions. Ignorance doesn't indicate a problem, just a lack of knowledge. The Headmistress seemed annoyed by Harry's version of her defense. She hadn't done anything wrong, but she still blames herself for not finding a way to save Neville. Harry suspected this was another time when Minerva wanted someone to lash out at her, but she'd been blameless. She's growing into her new position well, and if she is no Albus Dumbledore ... well, few are.

Harry sighed internally, people are so afraid of going first and looking foolish. "I can't believe you don't have questions. When I went through the full transcripts I had dozens."

"Such as?" The Headmistress asked.

Harry shook his head, "I don't want to prejudice things."

Hermione didn't say anything. She and Harry had already argued what it meant that her pouch and wand had been next to her bed when she awoke. Draco had apparently sent it up there at some point during the night. Harry just said that it means that Draco knew he couldn't smuggle them into Peverell, and thankfully didn't realize what he'd gotten. Draco had managed to acquire two of the three Deathly Hallows before even setting foot in Peverell, and he'd given both back. To Harry's mind, that meant Draco never even knew what he'd done. Hermione argued he'd done that fighting the Imperius. Now she'd conceded the point.

She argued against Draco last Spring, Harry thought. Now she defends him. But he understood the impulse. Harry still felt the urge to defend Draco. Why can't I ever have an enemy I instinctively dislike?

Amelia Bones spoke first, "What was Draco's original plan?"

Harry nodded, "I don't know. I can't see how this works unless Draco had a full fledged battle raging around him. He can't get at his equipment without some distraction. Part of me thinks Draco always intended Neville to die," Harry shot Hermione a glance, but again her face revealed nothing, "but he may have had another trick up his sleeve."

"Why now," Hermione asked quietly.

Harry nodded, "That's been troubling me. Undoubtedly the exact timing is convenience, but something changed. Maybe Draco just felt that he couldn't let things go on. It may be that the discovery of the Map gave him the impetus. I'm going to question Lockhart and Slughorn tomorrow. Maybe they can shed some light on this."

"If Draco did escape," asked Professor Asimov, "How?"

"Well, if he was Polyjuiced he may have just gotten away in the final minutes and walked out. He had to be gone before the full investigation, because then Aurors were checking everyone with Legillmency. But he could have dived out a hole. Even then, he'd have to make his way to the wards to avoid the anti-Portkey measures the Aurors raised around Hogwarts. Still, I can think of several ways around that. It doesn't matter too much, although it is an interesting question."

Harry couldn't bring himself to admit which answer he hoped was true. IF Draco lived.

"Auror Li didn't see a Portkey among Draco's items," said the Headmistress.

"Which may just mean that he didn't recognize it. That fits with Draco's modus operandi during the entire affair. We also don't know what Draco's third potion was. In any case, how Draco left isn't really as much of a concern as how we handle the fact that Draco might still be alive."

"You want us to announce that Draco survived?" Amelia Bones sounded incredulous.

"No!" Harry said abruptly, "Sorry, that wasn't my intent. We have to decide what we're going to do about the current situation. All of this happened because Draco didn't trust me. And, well, we've been lying. For a good cause, but I just thought perhaps we lay out my past to the Wizengamot and ..."

Now the room explodes in cross talk and challenges, Harry thought as the voices climbed over each other.

"Absolutely not," said Minerva McGonagall over the others, silencing them. "As someone who has experienced Harry Potter first hand, you do have your charms. But your natural tendencies make people slow to warm up to you and quick to judge. If they believed you were Voldemort, they would stop thinking."

"They would remember that you frightened a Dementor," Amelia Bones said, "and naturally go 'Aha! Of course!' Well, obviously Lord Voldemort frightens Dementors, that makes sense. It's a convenient, easy to believe narrative."

"Hermione destroyed five Dementors," Harry said, but he said it softly. He'd brought the others in for their political advice. It would be foolish to just reject it out of hand. "In any case, the story is already out there. If we say that yes, magically speaking I'm ... Voldemort's son, say ... we can point out I wasn't raised by him and his sins are not mine."

"Dumbledore knew," Hermione said, "and he didn't tell anyone."

Harry shook his head. "Dumbledore cheated, Hermione. He clearly had extra-temporal information that he used to maneuver me. Which means we can't really base our of decision making, apart from a moral standpoint, on him."

The discussion flared, growing more heated, before dimming again, and they did not break until well past midnight.

Chapter 58: Bluff and Double Bluff, Pt 5

"Plotters never violate the Rule of Three, Father?"

"They violate it all the time. The vast majority are idiots."

"And what are the remainder?"

"Desperate. Only the desperate take unreasonable risks."

- Lucius and Draco Malfoy

Monday, November 4th, 1991.

"Who can tell me what Generals Potter and Malfoy did wrong and why it is that General Granger earned ten Quirrell points in yesterday's battle?" Professor Quirrell's voice resonated throughout all of the Defense hall, echoed by the monitors in front of each student. Draco's head tilted almost imperceptibly downward as he felt a stab of shame. The shame of losing, publicly losing.

Bad enough to have lost at all, but to a Mudblood? Draco berated himself for a moment, as he'd been doing since losing the first battle to Hermione Granger the day before. But then he heard the voice of Father, who sometimes spoke inside of his head.

Anyone may lose, my son. I have lost. A dozen Lord Malfoys have lost innumerable times throughout history. There is no shame in losing. Only shame in admitting defeat. Lose in battle, never lose faith.

Draco raised his chin to compensate for the earlier drop, then raised it more. His hand shot up, joining dozens of others. He noticed that Hermione wore an annoyed look on her face.

Professor Quirrell turned towards Draco and paused in his relentless to-and-fro across the front of the room. "Yes, Mr. Malfoy? Tell the class your mistake."

"General Potter and I underestimated General Granger. She's apparently overcome her lack of fighting spirit," he said with a practiced bemusement, earning chuckles from the class. Vincent let out a snort that Draco now recognized as a measured ironic comment. Mr. Crabbe sported a surprisingly nuanced sense of humour.

Thank Merlin for the lessons in public speaking, Draco thought, not for the first time today.

"Correct," said Professor Quirrell, drawling the word out where others would pause, "but not complete. General Potter?"

"General Granger delegated and trusted her troops more, instead of having a rigid command structure," Harry Potter said, with an embarrassed look on his face. This hurts him, admitting his errors, and he doesn't hide showing it. It also struck Draco as an odd statement, at least if what he'd heard about the Chaos Legion's fluid command structure was true. Still, he'd noticed Harry's precision about his words. Perhaps General Potter was admitting more (and less) than first appeared. Perhaps Harry delegated, but didn't really trust them. Draco filed away the thought for further review.

Professor Quirrell's voice ended Draco's reverie. "Also correct, although delegating and trusting carry their own dangers, One example is the problem of communicating and coordinating in a rapidly changing environment. Ah, I see that Neville of Chaos," at this Professor Quirrell's thin lips turned ever so slightly upward, "has my answer."

Neville Longbottom let out a deep breath, like he'd been holding it. "When General Granger's army was revealed to be alive, they didn't adjust their strategy."

Professor Quirrell's head tilted ever so slightly to the side, like a bird interested in a shiny rock. "They formed an alliance, Mr. Longbottom, whereas just before General Potter had been employing a muggle device to eviscerate General Malfoy's shields. Which reminds me, I disallow muggle devices in the future, Mr. Potter. While I admire the cleverness behind it, it hardly strikes me as sporting to your fellow students for you to reach into your bag of tricks and"

"But General Malfoy was..." Harry started up.

"This is the Hogwarts School of Magic!" Professor Quirrell retorted, spinning to face Harry. His volume dropped back to normal, and he resumed his typical soothing lecture voice as he smiled.

"I only mention that in case it had slipped your mind, Mr. Potter. So if General Malfoy spends his time in the library," and with this, Professor Quirrell's smile broadened noticeably, and Draco felt a thrill as the Professor nodded in his direction, "studying supposedly-advanced spells that are clearly within the range of abilities of first year students - no matter what the Ministry says - then you can understand why I consider that a perfectly legitimate advantage. One that any of my apprentices can learn, should they choose to exert themselves. Incidentally, students who do so choose will find that particular variant of the Protego spell in the standard book of spells, third year. Of which there are multiple copies are in the library. A fact that had surely not escaped General Granger's notice, I imagine. There are nine standard variants, not all of which are within your grasp."

Draco followed Professor Quirrell's view as he swiveled his gaze to Harry Potter, who nodded and seemed satisfied by the answer. Professor Quirrell refocused on Neville. "Apologies, Mr. Longbottom, for my distraction. You say that the Generals did not modify their strategy, and I have responded that they formed an alliance. How do you answer that?"

Neville seemed to be having a problem dealing with suddenly being the focus of attention again, but he blurted out, "That wasn't really new, though was it? They could have done that earlier, but simply choose not to."

"Exactly," said Professor Quirrell, "allying was required for either of them to have a hope of winning, but it was not, by itself, up to the task. No doubt if General Potter had been thinking clearly he would have realized that he himself could have fixed the main weakness of General Malfoy's Protego spell - immobility - with his remaining troops. But he did not think of that. Apparently his cleverness is a limited resource, and he had run out."

Draco could see the barb had struck Harry, who now appeared deep in thought enumerating ways he could have done better. Draco realized that the statement didn't feel like it applied to him. There were several interpretations. One is that he was subtly courting Draco, but that didn't seem likely.

Does Professor Quirrell not expect me to be clever, as well?

"It also strikes me odd that General Malfoy instinctively offered to ally with the apparently weaker of two sides," Professor Quirrell continued, sparing a glance at Draco. That was my barb, and Draco realized the truth of it. He'd never considered asking for Hermione's help. It would never have worked, but Professor Quirrell is right.

"Perhaps I am wrong. Perhaps Harry Potter thought of several tricks and deliberately decided not to use them. Perhaps Draco Malfoy did consider allying with Hermione Granger and realized his offer would be rejected, and he would look foolish. Did he also consider bribing General Granger's troops? Perhaps with offer of money, or a favor, such as a date?"

He's truly evil, Draco thought as Vincent let out another snort, and even Gregory sniggered.

"I would have course applauded that. And then I would ban outside considerations, for the same reason I've banned muggle devices. And, to be clear, I am banning them from this point forward. But," Professor Quirrell paused, and this time there was no drawl, just a brief silence, "it is my suspicion - backed by considerable experience - that by that point both losing Generals were operating as though Confounded. The battle had raged on too long. They were in a desperate, unexpected situation. They were mentally tired. And at that point, they shut down and just took the path of least mental effort, despite the rather valiant magical effort displayed by all parties."

Professor Quirrell seemed to be fading, and he slid into his leather backed chair, but still spoke forcefully. "I hope that you never are on the losing side of a battle, my young apprentices. But I cannot promise you this. I do not blame people for battle fatigue, but it is real, as you've witnessed. I cannot teach you how to overcome it - not in a classroom anyway - but if you recognize it on the battlefield, that alone may inspire you to continue. To persevere. To make one more mental effort. It is a difficult lesson and there is no shame in having to learn it the hard war. Most wizards never learn it at all."

Draco glanced around the room. All the hands had fallen slowly down as Professor Quirrell had continued his lecture over the last few minutes, and many of the students looked thoughtful, at least among those not paying rapturous attention to the words being spoken.

"If it is any consolation to my defeated Generals, I suspect that if they had produced such efforts, it would have been for naught. For the bleak truth is: When you find yourself in a losing situation, you often lose. That is personally why I pretend to lose for that is a winning situation. But make no mistake, if you are actually losing even the most cunning stratagem does not guarantee victory. The soon-to-be victors are well placed to counteract superior cunning with their own lesser efforts, or even brute force. And my lesson to you: Try anyway! Any chance of victory is preferable to certain defeat. Do not act as though you were confounded! Maybe you will get lucky. Or perhaps the other forces will fall prey to overconfidence. Do not rely on luck, but do not discount it."

Professor Quirrell's voice was fading but still being repeated by the various monitors placed throughout the lecture hall. "In any case, if you are losing you have little left to lose. So - remain alive to your possibilities and you may yet remain alive."

Professor Quirrell barely got the words "Class dismissed" out of his mouth before he collapsed back into his chair, face lolling off to the side, eyes still open but apparently fast asleep. The monitors flickered out of existence as the class slowly got their feet.

March 7th, 1993, early am.

The battle ranged around Draco, hidden in a small closet, as he hurriedly worked but clumsily, hindered by hands much larger than he was used to. Draco's new hands didn't tremble, but their sheer size distracted him. Draco estimated his new body weighed nearly twenty stones, with height to match. His perspective was all wrong, too.

Earlier, Draco had hurriedly quaffed the second vial of polyjuice from the small spherical flask after adding the man's hair. And then poured Draco-laced polyjuice down the stunned man's throat. Much easier for a fully grown man to drag a small boy instead of the opposite.

We were insane, Neville, Draco thought. We should have just destroyed Harry's base of support and fled.

Draco felt the Philosopher's stone give a small twist in his hand. He set it aside and started to strip.

Draco's fingers moved clumsily as he stripped. Draco's robes had adjusted to his new size - as they were enchanted to do, but his handles felt alien as he undressed. He quickly slipped the tiny blond boy who used to be a man out of grossly over-sized robes and donned them, instinctively checking his pockets for any useful items. A spare wand, good. Draco slipped his own robes onto the other body. I seem so small. Draco's hands placed the silver ring he'd taken off earlier and slipped it onto the child's finger, then placed the Philosopher's stone on the slowly breathing chest and waited. The sounds of the battle grew closer, he could hear shouting and screams.

The stone twisted.

Draco took out his wand and leveled it towards the man now wearing his body.

"Avada Kedavra," Draco said quietly but nothing happened. How can I not do this? How can I fail now? Draco tried again but the spell didn't work.

I should want this man dead, Draco thought, he conspired to steal the Philosopher's Stone for himself. He no doubt planned on betraying me at the first opportunity. Draco needed this man dead and cast around for a moment before remembering he now inhabited the body of a monstrous adult and the 'man' he needed to kill was now a small child. Draco reached down and wrapped his arms around the now-tiny neck, gripping the side of the head. Draco saw his victim's eyes open wide, suddenly awake and afraid.

Draco twisted hard and heard the snap.

I never even knew his name. Father told me that would make it easier. Tears came to Draco's new eyes; he brushed them away. I knew this path ... no, that is a distancing thought, I knew my plan required this. A few deaths, to save many. Draco took the Sigil of House Malfoy and placed it in his doppelganger's hands, willing it to stay.

Draco glanced out of the room and tried to feel the shape of the battle. The experiences of the last two years hadn't prepared him for exactly this, but they mostly applied. Draco could hear another of Neville's arguments in his head, "We've been fighting three way battles for two years, and the other two sides won't even know there's a third army!"

Judging from the noise, Hogwart's had launched another assault. Black fog coursed through the hospital, obscuring everyone's vision and providing cover. Draco quickly grabbed the body and dragged it through the door, staying low. We've already won, Draco told himself as spells flew overhead. Even if I die. That thought calmed him down. His death would somehow make Neville's death fairer.

That thought is a pleasant falsehood, nothing more, Lucius said. A Malfoy cheats death hundreds of times before succumbing. Draco dragged the corpse to the middle of the room and left it there. He stood up and double checked, making sure the corpse looked like he had. Polyjuice made the body correct, but he inspected all the clothes and jewelry and placed a spare wand down on the ground. This is as good a place as any. Draco holstered his other stolen wand and grabbed the one he'd smuggled in his fake cane. He clutched it with both hands, it felt tiny now. Draco made his way toward the wall and - spotting a hole - sprinted the last few steps. Each stride covered a seemingly impossible distance.

Draco jumped through the hole in the wall and was outside in the clear night, falling. For a moment he felt frozen, staring at the moonlight above. Then sensation returned and he spun, rotating from the momentum of his jump and now Draco faced the ground below as it rushed up to meet him and Draco snapped the wand in half and felt the dislocating pull as his portkey dragged him away.

We did it, Neville. We were insane, but... Branches scraped Draco's face and he landed with a soft crunch into the dirt and leaves.

Draco rested in the ground for a moment, until finally he could think. Apparently portkeys do not change your height above ground, or the speed you were going. Or maybe that just costs extra. Draco blinked twice, tears coming out of his eyes. He rolled over. The canopy overhead blocked out the stars and the moon light. Draco could hear the battle raging, just barely. No portkey could take him outside of Hogwarts, not if aurors had set up anti-portkey enchantments. But those only warded the edges of Hogwarts. He'd only needed to escape from the battle, so a fast jump into the Forbidden Forest worked.

Draco rolled over, casting his eyes around for the small stone cairn he'd built last weekend. It should be nearby. As scary as the Forbidden Forest had felt last fall or even last weekend, at least it had been daytime. In the darkness, Draco heard every chitter and screech and distant moan, a small symphony of unexplained sounds hinting at unseen dangers. Draco saw the pile of rocks and pulled himself up to his feet and walked over. He carefully started take apart the mound.

Did you plan on sacrificing yourself, Neville? I didn't want to admit it, but you more than anyone hated Voldemort. Draco had emphasized that he didn't think Harry would turn into Voldemort, still Neville had latched onto that fact. Draco knew it had been a risk that Neville would commit suicide instead of risk failure, perhaps because of fear, perhaps because of some nobility towards his parents loss, but Draco had minimized the risk in his mind. I never should have involved you, Neville. Just trusted my own judgement. I thought I could guide you, but that was just hubris. This is my fault. Draco tossed each rock aside in a different direction and recited the pertinent rule of the plan to himself. Do not leave any trace. The plan won't work if you leave a trace.

Nobody had read Draco's mind during the Battle. That was the real risk. You can't not think of a plan while carrying out the steps. If his silver ring had detected any mental intrusion Draco would have had to kill, right away. No hesitation. That had been another real risk, that he'd stumble onto someone paranoid and clever, like Alastor Moody. But that risk had been there every since he recovered his memories. It was one of Neville's more compelling arguments. Draco couldn't plan around Harry for years without involving other people, not unless each and every one were an Occlumens and trustworthy, a rare combination. This plan (this insane plan) involved lots of moving parts, but waiting and operating in solitude involved it's own set of risks. Easier to enumerate, but just as dangerous. My only excuse is that we were truly desperate.

Leaving the ring behind hurt, it was a valuable tool to a plotter too young to know when someone was reading his mind. Leaving everything behind hurt. But it was necessary.

Even if I die tomorrow, I'll die anonymously. It will take weeks for them to untangle this. With the Marauder's Map Slughorn will generate months of problems for Harry. That, combined with Draco's other surprises would drastically curtail Harry Potter's political power over the next few years. In that area, if nothing else, Draco could be sure.

A twig snapped. It was a surprisingly mundane sound in the middle of the forest and Draco turned around. His mind rebelled against looking at the figure in the Armageddon Robe, but he saw the wand pointed at him.

"What are you doing, Letholdus? Trying to escape with the stone by yourself?" The robe made the words sound like the screeching of nails on a chalkboard in Draco's mind. But Draco didn't recognize the speech pattern, or the wand.

Another attacker, probably watching from outside to delay the aurors.

"Escaping, but without the stone. The battle is lost, something went wrong and they were all over us from the beginning. All we can do is escape. I stashed some supplies earlier, just in case. Come on, help me."

"I'll take those, step away." Draco stepped away. It was hopeless. He couldn't out-duel any of the attackers or aurors, and this wasn't a duel. His wand was holstered. Draco could summon his cane but that would ruin all he'd worked for. No, better to die. Dying was always the most likely outcome. Anyway, it would be disrespectful to Neville to throw it all away to save myself.

Given that, it was hopeless. Draco felt so tired of it all. He closed his eyes and took a deep breath, resting.

And they were mentally tired... if you recognize it on the battlefield, that alone may inspire you to continue. To persevere. To make one more mental effort.

Draco opened his eyes, the memory of Professor Quirrell's lecture shocking him out of his reverie. What do I know? What straws can I grasp at?

Draco considered. His attacker knew his name, at least the name of Draco's body. They clearly weren't friends, not from the gesture - although he dare not read much into the tone of someone wearing Armageddon Robes. But, Draco was still alive and not killed outright. Presumably this attacker was watching to prevent treachery by Lockhart and Draco, a part of the plan not told to him before hand. And why would they tell him? Those all struck Draco as reasonable assumptions. Time to decide on a strategy.

Bribery? No, anything he offered could simply be taken. Pleading? Laughable. Karkaroff had assembled an elite group of murderers (like me, a small part of Draco interjected). These people had plotted for a month, fraying each other's nerves. Draco imagined they'd bickered and snapped with barely restrained hostility, vying for dominance. In any case, pleading might betray the fact that he wasn't Letholdus.

For once, Draco lacked a social advantage. What advantage did he have? The robed figure had pulled off the last few rocks and found the waiting pouch, which contained all of the money Draco had dared to smuggle out of his vault without risking discovery or looking like he'd been planning to run, along with some gold and jewels. Neville's supplies were stashed somewhere else, but Draco didn't have time to go out Neville's escape route.

It was still a handsome sum, several years of living expenses. He'd been spending extravagantly before he started this plan, which would help hide the wealth missing from his vault. That pouch represented a grand haul for any would-be thief, Mundungus Fletcher would have fainted if he'd glimpsed it. But that pouch was paltry compensation if you'd planned to steal immortality itself. Draco watched, thinking, and suddenly realized his advantage. It was admittedly slim, but if he failed... he had nothing to lose. And if he failed he'd leave no trace.

A win-win, Draco chuckled to himself morbidly.

"That's just the money. I'll go get the other stash. We'll need both to escape cleanly." The figure threw back her hood and the look she gave Draco - a look of greed mixed with caution- buoyed his spirits. Not only was she interested, Draco could now read her expressions, no longer shrouded in the hood of her robes. He didn't recognize her, which just confirmed that she wasn't part of the plan. At least the plan Draco knew about.

Draco took several steps to the left. He'd gathered his bearing now, and spoke confidently. "I know what all of you think of me, but there was always a chance of this bubbling over and I made preparations. I'm sorry, but what do you expect? Me to rot in jail with the rest of them?"

Draco (Letholdus, remember? Father's voice, said. You are Letholdus. Don't think of yourself as Draco) started walking more briskly, simply assuming that he would not get killed. He was judging his words based on watching the witch's reactions and right now instinct told Draco that her greed would keep him alive a bit longer. The witch had cast several spells and poured out the contents of the pouch before quickly returning them.

Just money, like I said. "What's in the other pouch?" she asked.

"Things we'll need to escape. Once the battle is done the aurors will search the entire grounds. So I stocked ward breakers and a portkey. Only one, but we can share it." Draco hurried as much as he dared. He needed her greedy and suspicious.

"Stop." Draco stopped, obediently. Draco was sweating, but that helped. Sweating is a natural reaction of being so close to death, and she'll naturally interpret that I'm afraid of her.

"Show me," she commanded. Draco took another step, but she fired off a spell to stop him. The witch shook her head, her short cropped blond hair reflecting what little moonlight got through the canopy. Draco, shoulders slouched, pointed to a spot a few feet ahead of him.

"Buried at that tree trunk. Look. Please. We can share the port key. If we both escape, we can split up, and you have a better chance," Draco's voice took on a pleading tone, an edge of desperation, but the witch's smile kept growing as she slid past Draco, safely out his reach. She continued towards the tree, keeping a careful eye on Draco.

"Please," Draco said as the triffid's vine snatched the witch off the ground.

Draco dove down, dodging the wild spells she fired. The screams intensified and Draco scrambled behind cover and got out his own wand. Well, Letholdus' wand. There was a burst of flame, instantly illuminating the forest with a shockingly bright orange. She was trying to burn the triffid. Draco fired Expelliarmus at the vine, casting over and over again and the witch's frustrated scream let him know he'd scored. A moment later, the sound of rending flesh made Draco's shoulder ache and the screaming continued. The orange glow brightened.

Draco didn't want to look, but he watched. The wet sounds drowned out the rest of the forest. Draco steadied his wand Accio pouch! and his money flew over into his hand. The witch had stopped fighting, and was slowly disappearing into the Triffid's grotesque maw. Draco almost took her wand, then realized that would be a mistake. He didn't need it anyway. Draco walked away from the triffid at a brisk pace, but he heard more twigs snapping and two voices talking.

Aurors. They'd followed the witch or heard the screams. Or seen the fire, obviously. They were flying towards him.

Draco scanned about. He'd used his last advantage dealing with the witch. Even if it was just a single auror, he couldn't very well feed him to the Triffid. ("Once a triffid has eaten, it's safe to walk right up next it for up as long as two days or so," Professor Lockhart had explained to the class, after Draco's near death. Draco probably could have picked up the pouch off the ground, but he hadn't felt like performing that experiment).

"I couldn't finish it, Headmaster." He said, quietly to himself. "Not by myself. Hopefully I've done enough." He took the wand and pointed it at himself. He couldn't afford to be taken alive. They'd read his mind. Ideally he'd feed himself to a Triffid to destroy the evidence but perhaps if he found a small hiding spot... I think, at this moment, I hate myself enough to do this.

Draco hadn't given up, but fatigue engulfed him. He couldn't think clearly. Instead of focusing on the problem at hand he instinctively thought about the conversation with Dumbledore that had set his plan in motion, how the Headmaster had told him of the prophecy that Harry Potter would destroy the world, and given Draco the burden of saving the world. Draco turned and started moving away from the incoming sound, but they were in brooms and Draco dare not cast Lumos. It would be a long trek, at night, through the Forbidden Forest. But he had nothing to lose, and he started walking as fast as he dared.

I still have allies here, Dumbledore had said, and help is always available at Hogwarts to those who ask.

"Please, I need help," Draco whispered.

And disappeared in flash of fire.

"I saw a flash," said Auror Edebus, wand out, as the two brooms came crashing through the brush.

Auror Phaethon looked carefully around. "Yeah, it's called a fire. Probably just some rotting log catching. ... oh. Man." He dismounted slowly and cautiously and moved towards the flailing vines engulfed in flames. He peered into the fire, and heard quiet squishing noises underneath the crackling flames. "Looks like we found our straggler. Stumbled onto a Triffid."

"Saves us the trouble," said Edebus, starting to extinguish the fire.

Draco Malfoy appeared inside the edge of the forest in a flash of fire, as though he'd been burning in two places at once. Fawkes scream of victory echoed inside his head, for a moment, and then there was another flash and the Phoenix was gone. Draco blinked a few times as the sudden darkness left him blind.

"Fawkes?" Draco asked. But there was no light at all, except the gentle moonlight.

"Thank you, Headmaster." The plan could go on. Draco couldn't very well kill Harry Potter, the Headmaster had told him that. Not that Draco would want to. But now he could disappear and spend the years gathering the resources he'd need to quietly oppose Harry. Not without fear, but with some semblance of order. By then maybe he'd have a better plan to slow down the inevitable.

Draco couldn't save the world forever, but he could prolong it for years. Indefinitely, perhaps.

Delay is the strongest form of denial, after all.

Eyes adjusted, Draco looked out of the forest. He was at the rendezvous, at the edge of the forest by the lake, well away from the castle. Draco wanted to go peer down into the lake and take a good look at his reflection, but that was folly and vanity. In any case, that could wait. Draco looked around. It was just a few dozen steps to the edge of the grounds. He quickly cast a few spells of concealment and Quietus, took a few deep breaths, and ran across the small clearing until he was off the Hogwarts ground, confident that the wards would not raise the alarm at his passage. And they did not.

No longer rushed, Draco Malfoy turned and took one last look at Hogwarts, gently holding the delicate spherical flask in his hands, feeling the smooth glass. He placed it inside his pocket.

We did it. We actually did it. He savored the moment, letting satisfaction wash over him. He'd have years for remorse and regrets later. Possibly even decades to contemplate all that he'd given up and lost. Just this once, I get to win. There were broomsticks moving throughout the air, apparently the battle had ended. Draco's eyes lingered on the main gate, then settled on the castle of Hogwarts School of Magic.

Tomorrow he'd decide where to settle. Randomly. Even Harry Potter couldn't predict randomness.

"Neville of Chaos, Scion of House Longbottom," Draco whispered to nobody, "Goodbye." Only Hogwarts heard his voice and the tinkling cracks when Draco crushed the flask through the cloth, triggering the portkey that whisked him out of Scotland.

Chapter 61: Beginnings

August 1st, 1993

Duarte let out a slow approving whistle as he stared at the nearly two meter tall brute, height made more impressive by the lack of hair to aid it. His bald head reflected most of the shaft of the afternoon light streaking in through the bar window. The man was dressed in a simple black T-shirt and jeans, and kept his eyes locked on Duarte. The man's physique looked natural, not like one of those American movie stars who spent hours in the gym.

Duarte nodded. "Yes, the boss will like you. A bruiser everyone can fear without shame. Very intimidating. What's your name?"

The man stared at him, gaze hard, for several seconds before finally saying, "Alexio."

Duarte raised an eyebrow and slid his gaze back to Tomas. "Well, Alexio, I need to confer with friend here," and he stepped over to the other side of the bar.

"Where did you find this one, Tomas? Is he trying to pull some tough guy routine on us? Not that he doesn't look it, but does he know who we are?" Duarte nodded over to the bartender who poured out a shot of bourbon - the good stuff - and took a drink. "Or is he on drugs, and has to work off a debt?

"No drugs, just an idiot. He's slow to answer, barely says anything, but if you put him in a scrape he's fine. Not a great fighter, but does he have to be? We can do the talking, he can tag along and look scary..."

Draco had christened himself Alexio, and refused to think of himself by any other name. Until he learned Occlumency, it was too dangerous. Alexio watched Tomas talk conspiratorially with the new man, the shorter one who hadn't mentioned his name. Tomas was more of a middle man, but the short one worried Draco. He looked dangerous, like he'd had to compensate for his size to demonstrate his value. He'd probably even been boasting about how the big ones are usually not so tough, but Alexio hadn't understood much. Even the simple question, one on the first page of any language book, had taken him precious seconds to work out. It wasn't like a classroom or tutoring - everyone spoke fast.

Tomas and the short man had moved over to the other side of the bar to conspire about him. Hopefully they hadn't realized how little he grasped. But this was easier, now he didn't have to focus on the words. Alexio could read the obvious greed in their faces. They'd dump their work on him and pay him too little. Alexio walked a dangerous path, but not in the sense that he'd be in much physical danger. Even a typical second year could deal with muggles, if they put their mind to it, and Alexio was in no way typical. He'd been practising a few wandless stunning hexes, typically targeting obnoxious passersby late at night. They shouldn't have worked, but they did. Perhaps his earlier tutoring paid off, or perhaps it was the physical age of the body. It was an interesting theoretical question, but he didn't have time to experiment.

Navigating the muggle world had dangers, and so he'd tested his skills, but he hoped to mostly hide them for the next year and practice alone, at his hideout. Casting spells in public risked alerting the local aurors while he clearly would be pegged as an outsider. Hiding had the less obvious (but much more important) risk - Harry would be actively consolidating power while Alexio waited in safety. No, Alexio knew he needed to start now. Because at some point, he would have enough power to be a threat to Harry Potter, and Alexio needed to make absolutely sure that his backstory did not simply start in 1993, with him as a newcomer who didn't speak the language. He needed to be someone who always spoke eloquently, but had chosen not to. Someone that had stories about him that easily predated his arrival.

Luckily Alexio had Vincent's example as a prototype. Be big, act stupid, speak only when absolutely necessary. Never break eye contact first, no matter how much you were afraid. Knowing he didn't need a wand in his hand helped calm his nerves. Alexio glanced over at the two, who were laughing now. They had made their decision. He turned his gaze to the television. The announcers still spoke too quickly (except for the news announcers) but they tended to have clear diction and usually never said anything complicated.

Tomas saw Alexio, sitting on the other side of the bar and watching them impassively for a few seconds before his eyes flickered over to the television and started watching the random trash it played. He and Duarte walked back over to Alexio, and Duarte slapped the big man on the back.

"Well, Alexio, it appears we will be working together. The only thing you should know is, I prefer redheads. So no making moves on any of them. Got it?" Duarte said.

Alexio just let out an amused snort, shrugging his shoulders. Tomas laughed.

"And how are you feeling tonight, little one?" Afonso Farias asked as he gently kissed his daughter's forehead. He could feel the slight fever in his lips, still there, but much reduced from the summer, when things had looked bleak. The doctors couldn't explain it, one had simply said it was a miracle but the others just quietly admitted that there was still a lot to learn about human physiology, and the body had defenses they didn't understand.

"I feel good, Father," Ana said. "Nanny read to me after lunch. We had soup for lunch," she added.

"That's good," Afonso added. He'd of course gotten a detailed update from Ana's nanny when he'd arrived home, and he knew that his daughter still slept about half the day. Her strength was returning slowly, but it was better than the alternative. It was barely sunset, and already her eyelids were drooping. "Perhaps you should get some sleep, my sweet," he said.

"You also, Father. You look very tired," she said, but her voice was already fading. Afonso nodded. He'd felt tired for the last year, strained by the experience of caring for his late wife and his recovering daughter. He watched her fall into a peaceful slumber for a few minutes, then went into the kitchen and prepared a small dinner and ate in front of the television, watching Baovista's latest match. They'd just been promoted to the second division, so they were getting thrashed. The score was still nil-nil, but it was only a matter of time. Afonso sighed as he cleaned up the dishes. No point in watching, he was tired. A small noise startled him and he turned to see a large looming figure in the kitchen point a stick and say a word. Afonso froze, muscles locked, and crashed into the floor. The man - nearly two meters tall and with curly black hair and a hardened jaw, looked unkempt, like he hadn't shaved in days, but he easily picked up Afonso and through him over his shoulder, saying nothing.

Afonso panicked, unable to move. Why am I frozen? And what did the man say? It wasn't Portuguese, it sounded vaguely like English. Or corrupted Latin, perhaps. Playing the scene back in his mind, Afonso was startled to see he was being carried up the attic ladder and started to whisper a prayer.

As he finished, the figured deposited him into a comfortable leather chair. The attic wasn't like he'd left it, full of boxes. The clutter had been replaced by a reasonable (if spartan) set of furniture. Afonso's eye's glanced around and saw a desk, bookshelf, chair, and a small mattress on the floor. The figure walked over to the small television placed in the center of his view and turned it on, pushing a VCR tape into the machine. He then simply went back down the ladder.

The tv screen flickered for a moment, and then Afonso saw ... himself.

"Do not be afraid, little conqueror," he said. Little conqueror was a nickname Afonso's father had bestowed on him when he was eight. "The man who did this to you is our guest. He is a warlock, or some such. He asked us for help with learning the language and the city, and to hide him. In exchange, he is helping Ana. He cannot cure her, that is beyond his power, but you've seen he does have power. But he is helping. And he has promised that once he is fluent in Portuguese he will find someone who can cure her. Perhaps we should not believe him. But what can we do? A few hours of lessons most nights, and then we forget about him. Perhaps in a year, he will be gone. It is a fair deal."

While listening with growing confusion, Afonso could hear the man downstairs, making a plate of food for himself. By the time the tape ended, the heavy footsteps climbed back up the ladder. The man set down a rather large sandwich on his writing desk and then took out his wand and said a few words. Prepared this time, Afonso recognized the words. Finite Incantatem.

"Good evening, Professor Farias, and my apologies," the man said. He spoke slowly and carefully, as if following the carpenter's adage to measure twice and cut only once. When he finished speaking he set down his wand and picked up the sandwich, then took a bite. Afonso stood up slowly and cautiously. He started to say something, then paused. The man - the warlock, Afonso had said on the tape - stopped chewing and swallowed.

"I know what you are thinking. About the police," the man said, then took another bite, then picked up a sheet of paper and walked over and deposited it on the tray table besides the leather chair. Afonso picked it up. The handwriting's elegance didn't hide the clumsiness of the language, but clearly the man had a much better grasp of written Portuguese than spoken. Or perhaps just had more time to compose his thoughts.

Apart from the fact that you trust your words on the television, I am helping your daughter's recovery. Private tutoring is a small price to pay for that, even if it must be clumsy because you do not remember each session. And since you always ask each night, removing your memories is as much for your safety as mine, as I have powerful enemies who are hunting for me. And you know the police would laugh at you, or much worse.

As for my name, we've generally gone with Orpheus. Please critique the writing on this letter while I finish eating. Also, can you tell where I am from?

"You are English, Orpheus," Afonso said, voice steadying after a few words.

"How do you know?" asked Orpheus, before taking another bite.

"Your accent is good, but your sentence construction betrays you. And in any case, no native would consider going to the police a serious threat. At least, not from someone who wasn't wealthy." Afonso spoke slowly, but Orpheus repeated the sentence back, emphasizing a few words, which Afonso translated into English. It took several repetitions, but Orpheus grasped it. He is, actually, a surprisingly attentive student.

Orpheus nodded at the sentence, one he grasped its meaning, and chuckled at the last part before swallowing the last of the sandwich.

Afonso looked up. "That is it, isn't it? You will consider yourself fluent when I cannot guess your accent?" While Orpheus struggled with that sentence, particularly with the word fluent, Afonso walked over to the bookshelf and read the titles. An entire row of books on elementary Portuguese, and some tourist guides for Brazil and also Portugal. More interesting were the scrolls and ancient looking tomes that could have been pulled from a movie or child's fairy tale. English books with bizarre yet somehow mundane sounding names, Intermediate Transfigurations, Practical Divinations for Everyone, Runic Lore, and seven volumes of Miranda Grawshank's Standard Book of Spells. Names that implied that 'wizard' might simply be another trade, like professor, lawyer, mechanic or scientist. Beside the bookshelf a small cauldron bubbled quietly.

"Yes," Orpheus said. "You said another year to be fluent. Ana should be fine within a few months. I cannot cure her. Healing magics are not ... mine. I can brew palliative formulas."

"A surprisingly complex word, palliative," Afonso said.

"Which you taught me. Now, the letter? I've written more, Correct them for mistakes. Formal language for writing, common language for speaking. Correct anything I say. We have ninety minutes left, to work. Then we both sleep."

Author's Note - The final chapter will be posted on Christmas Eve.

Chapter 63: Destroying the Legend, Epilogue Pt 1

"Once I saw a Devil in a flame of fire,

who arose before an Angel that sat on a cloud,

and the Devil uttered these words.

'The worship of God is:

Honoring his gifts in other men each according to his genius,

and loving the greatest men best:

those who envy or calumniate great men hate God,

for there is no other God.'"

Harry James Potter-Evans-Verres ran through his checklist as he floated underwater, just outside the arch leading into Atlantis.

He held an actual laminated checklist. Studies done nearly two-hundred and fifty years ago conclusively demonstrated that even experts with thousands of hours of training - like pilots and surgeons - sometimes forgot a critical step. Harry considered himself the world's foremost living authority on Atlantis. But he had no actual experience with it, yet.

Nobody did. The greatest living expert merely meant Harry was the least ignorant. He went methodically down his checklist to ensure he hadn't forgotten anything. He reviewed the defenses he expected to encounter and the correct countermeasures, from first down to the last. Reminders as to which spells to favor. He flipped the checklist over to the back, then went to the second page.

Even by Harry's rather demanding standards he felt prepared. As prepared as possible. Harry had spent two decades practicing for this moment in an underwater training facility.

Despite what earlier conservative politicians proclaimed, you could eventually disband a government agency without violent uprising. All you had to do was make the effective human life span "As much as you'd care to enjoy" and spend several generations training people to think. Once you did that even politicians started widening their time horizons and raising their level of discourse.

It took decades longer than he'd hoped. But there had been progress.

Humanity no longer lived solely on one single frail eggshell. Bowie Base One supported nearly a million souls. The Sovereign Moon held a seat on the U.N. Security Council. Some time ago the American government ministers (or more likely, their constituents) had read the writing on the wall. Humanity had far fewer problems during the Third Enlightenment (as the History books called it), but they had problems nonetheless. Each innovation usually brought more rewards than challenges, but there were constant issues to deal with.

And even when all your problems were smaller, you still spent most of your time dealing with them. Problems - no matter how big or small - required resources to be allocated efficiently.

Once corporations routinely captured and mined asteroids and frontier towns had sprung up on other planets and moons, space had long ago ceased to be a 'research' problem, and just one of scale. The (original) world's nations had other problems to address and so a controversial measure proposed by the Distinguished Gentlewoman from Costa Rica made its way into law.

N.A.S.A had been privatized in 2089.

Harry had snapped up a fair percentage of the assets to prepare for his inevitable exploration of Atlantis. He kept one of the original Apollo space suits back at Hogwarts because obviously they deserved to be seen, and few people alive had a real appreciation for that part of humanity's history. Publicly buying space trinkets was just Harry being Harry, snapping up mementos from a bygone age few remembered was the sort of thing people expected Harry Potter to do. It was no stranger than anything else he'd done. If Harry could hide his true intentions by publicly appearing to be what the media portrayed him as, that was fine with him. A good move has multiple purposes. If Harry could inspire his students with a few props that was an added benefit.

But as he made the purchase Harry knew that one day he'd swim into Atlantis.

Once he discovered where it was.

He'd started that task even before his marriage. Scholars told him Atlantis would be impossible to find. All legends agreed there were no clues and no traces of the civilization to be found. But that had not been tested experimentally. He started researching, but just in case there really weren't clues or tricks, that left Harry one option.

He brute forced it.

Before Harry celebrated his thirtieth birthday he'd discovered a renowned Muggle exploring the ocean floor and mapping its depths. Harry Potter simply introduced himself, demonstrated enough magic to be convincing, revealed everything he knew about Atlantis and swore him to secrecy.

What explorer could resist?

Even during the decades Harry Potter spent petrified his high-tech search for Atlantis continued. Long after Harry's dispirited acolytes had thrown their hands up in frustration and abandoned their tasks, one man hunted for Atlantis. After a century, it remained undiscovered.

Harry - awake again - went back and re-examined the data. A painstaking analysis revealed ... nothing.

Harry ran the analysis again - this time under the watchful eyes of Aurors - they noticed some discrepancies and the tell-tale sign of Obliviation. Harry narrowed down the search to a few specific sites. After that it was a matter of time, and after another decade, the location.

As far as Harry could tell, James Cameron was the first, second and fourth person to discover the entrance to Atlantis - only to have his memory altered each time.

Now Harry floated in front of the gate, giddy.

Harry had been happy most of his life, but bouts of giddy-ness had become increasingly rare. Harry speculated that giddy-ness (closely related to surprise) followed a pattern similar to the Prime Number Theory and became more infrequent as you got older, but never really disappeared.

Unlike primes and pure maths (which followed their own deep mysteries) Harry could adjust his expected giddyness by trying new things. Harry resolutely ignored all arguments that other people could do this. Atlantis was not his life's work, but it had always been there, in the background, and he was not about to give into those who said it was too dangerous for him. So he put aside all the words from the people who told him to delegate. Thankfully Luna wasn't one of them.

But he listened to their arguments.

Harry might be risking his life, but life was meant to be lived. Still, he'd listened. He'd taken every precaution suggested and even more. All he could think of.

His backed Bubble Head spell with state of the art rebreather equipment, and then scuba equipment. And an emergency rebreather. He had a plastic bag full of gillyweed in case things got desperate and he decided to stay, and five portkeys to scattered safe spots at a variety of depths (to avoid the bends). One portkey led a pressurized chamber in London, with healers waiting. Legend said you couldn't Apparate into Atlantis but no countermeasures prevented leaving, assuming you didn't take anything with you.

The stories - evidence was a strong word, too strong for his research - felt accurate. Harry knew that wasn't evidence, but evidence was not forthcoming.

Eventually Plupplup and Blboblb - the Mermish Aurors who'd demanded that Harry tell them the location of Atlantis so it could be investigated 'by the proper authorities' - had blown bubbles of exasperation and agreed to swim just outside Atlantis and allow Harry his moment.

For anyone else (well, almost anyone else) they'd have ignored his complaints and gone on their own.

Harry knew how to use the awe his name inspired. Blboblb and Plupplup had asked him nicely instead of simply shutting him down when they'd first visited him, decades ago. After Harry demurred, they placed a bewildering array of what they considered ridiculous demands. They expected Harry to object, after which they would go over his head. In the name of safety. Harry's safety.

They'd heard the legends of Harry Potter. But they didn't understand them. Not yet.

Harry complied with their demands.

He turned over every scrap of lore about Atlantis (except its location) and agreed that he'd have to best a crack Mermish Auror Trio in underwater combat before he'd swim through the gates. Harry also agreed that his test would involve situations where he'd swim in without advanced knowledge of the territory set up with whatever non-lethal trap they desired.

The Aurors complained that they had much better facilities for this. Harry privately agreed, but didn't want to publicly spend years training with Merfolk. Even the Muggle press would grasp the implications. But he'd taken sabbaticals at his American retreat for decades. That would arouse no suspicion. Harry un-mothballed an old NASA underwater training facility, tossed Plupplup the keys and said to call when they were ready.

Only then did the two mermen stop and really think about Harry Potter's childhood, before he became famous.

They set off to work.

Harry hadn't had that much fun in decades. It was like the childhood he'd never finished.

It took years. The Aurors felt surprised after they'd defeated Harry the first time. It had been ... easy. Harry Potter boasted respectable fighting talent, but the world had caught up during his years of stasis. He kept surprises up his sleeves but he'd taught his students well. Neither merman had Harry's innate cleverness, but they'd been diligent, and had been taught well by students of Harry's techniques.

Harry thanked the Aurors for the battle, learned from his mistake, and improved his plan. The next battle took longer.

Harry lost. He reviewed, learned, and studied. Harry Potter had all the time in the world. He kept up with his other duties, disappearing for a long weekend here and there to relax. Nobody really noticed. Harry was never particularly social, but he kept up correspondences. Harry lost his third battle and the fourth. As he lost battles he won over the Aurors' respect, as they learned the fundamental truth about him.

Harry Potter was not a God, just a clever man in an increasingly clever world. A world which (thankfully) no longer needed him, but respected his position and the influence he'd had. Harry had drifted into legend - for a while - but after he'd been revived he drifted back out of legend as people met him and judged him. The clever ones realized that he'd done everything with the tricks he'd taught them. He might have new tricks (there were always new tricks) but now they understood his techniques, even if they didn't always use them.

The world had thanked him, rewarded him well, listened to his advice and humoured Harry. They let him do pretty much anything he wanted, within reason. And sometimes beyond reason, at least in this case. That's what the Aurors had initially done. But as they defeated him over and over with less and less margin for error they watched the smiling man thank them, retreat, recover, regroup and rejoin the fight. Within two years Harry was a knowledgeable underwater tactician, albeit with physical skills only equal to a Mermish teenager.

Within five years, he routinely defeated unsuspecting Mermish Aurors in underwater duel.

After ten years Blboblb formally withdrew his objection. Harry Potter said there was no rush and he still had much to learn. After twenty years he'd defeated every challenge they could think of.

Then - and only then - Harry started preparations in earnest. He could finally see the endgame.

It had been fun. He thought he probably could have done it ten years, maybe eight. You can't rush physical skills. But he'd only spent a third of his time preparing for Atlantis. He'd had policies to craft, made sure to spend time with all the friends he accumulated over his life. As Harry said, there was no rush, and much more important matters to attend to.

The melding of Science and Magic meant barriers fell at an amazing pace.

Practically every day another iota of enlightenment could be squeezed from the advances. Every decade saw another major discovery. Grasping the implications an exploring them was Harry's full time job. The speed of light hadn't fallen. There were still hopes, but the maths were difficult. Research was slow and (by definition) had no fixed endpoint. Humanity had time to expand but eventually even the solar system would get full.

Births had fallen dramatically, but not nearly as dramatically as deaths.

Construction of the Dyson Disk had already started. It wouldn't house anyone for centuries and would probably never be finished. For now, they were only using materials already in orbit, but at some point those would run out ... by now most people doubted that the speed of light would ever be defeated.

Harry demurred an opinion. Prophecy was a tricky thing. Harry was just a man, but he had insider information. and how could he destroy the very stars if he couldn't get to them? In any case, assuming that they were stuck in this solar system was practical for now, so Harry just shrugged his shoulders and let the physicists do their work.

Harry's other main task was the same it had ever been. Encouraging and educating humanity. Now - thanks to his legend - that task consumed most of his time. if not much of his thoughts.

Harry had a canned intro he used during the numerous speeches he gave. Commencement speeches at Schools of Wizardry around the world were all basically the same. The speaker, some accomplished whitchard who seemed ancient to hir teenaged students but was a century Harry's junior, would extoll Harry's accomplishments - all long overshadowed by those who stood on his shoulders - and end with something like "I am honoured to present your speaker, the Legend, The Boy-Who-Lived, Harry Potter!"

Harry had his speech memorized, but held a note card with the Symposiarch's name. (The sole item on his "Speech" preparation checklist). Harry would smile and nod or wave as the mood struck him, then go into his speech.

"Thank you, but I would like to remind insert previous speaker's title and name here that we live in the Age of Symbiosis. I am not a legend, just a man. Perhaps a man ahead of his time, as people say. But times have caught up and surpassed me. The times have surpassed us all, even you who are about to embark on your new adventures. Our worlds are too big for any one person to explore, but that also means that they are big enough that any one person can find something new. You can be the first to glimpse some distant vista or uncover some new scientific principle. Build a better boggart trap. Invent a new flavor of ice cream. Age is no barrier. The only barriers exist inside you. If you have a strong desire, a good work ethic, a bit of cleverness, and the courage to believe in yourself, you can do anything. Those four attributes make the Herald of a little school I attended long ago and ran a while later. You may have heard of it."

Harry would wait for the polite laughter at his unfunny joke to die down before continuing.

"They say I'm a legend, but I'm just a man. There are no more mystical figures of legend. As a former legend I can tell you a secret: Not only are there no more, there never were. No legends. Just people. Any of you ... no make that all of you ... could become what people call a legend. But if you do you'll learn what I know. You'll feel the same. If you become a quote legend unquote you'll get there the way any quote normal person does. Because there are just people. There are no legends."

That was another applause line, and every time when Harry gave his speech he paused for the claps and murmured approvals.

But during that moment - before he pivoted into the main topic, whatever lesson he felt like discussing that day - as he said the final words and explained that there were no legends, while he waited for the applause to die...

In that moment a small voice in his head always spoke up. To chide Harry and remind him.

There is still one legend left.

That voice that kept Harry focused during the long decades. That voice - which sometimes named Gryffindor, sometimes Slytherin, sometimes Ravenclaw but usually Hufflepuff - strengthened Harry's resolve to complete the Herculean tasks set before him by those Aurors. That voice forced him to smile when he wanted to rant, to persevere past most people's endurance.

That was the voice Harry worked to quiet. And on this day he would succeed. Harry Potter swam through the gates of Atlantis.

The time had come to destroy one more legend and rescue one man.

Chapter 65: The Marriage of Heaven & Hell, Epilogue Pt 3

"did he not mock at the sabbath,

and so mock the sabbath's God?

murder those who were murdered because of him?

turn away the law from the woman taken in adultery?

steal the labor of others to support him?

bear false witness when he omitted making a defense before Pilate?

...

I tell you, no virtue can exist with breaking these ten commandments.

Jesus was all virtue, and acted from impulse, not from rules."

They swam towards the agora, their conversation businesslike and focused solely on the present. Schools of fish danced around Atlantis. Harry and Alexio watched the darting silvery forms and leveled their wands towards any who swam too near. But no group approached too closely, they always veered away. Sometimes a school briefly split into two before inevitably rejoining along a path angled safely away from the two wizards.

Alexio and Harry had already encountered a Chinese wizard solemnly standing in Taoist robe and gently waving a hand fan made of crane feathers. He appeared in the distance, standing inside a large room-sized bubble that seemed to follow his will. Spotting them, the wizard pointed his fan towards Harry and Alexio and the bubble approached, perhaps propelled by advantageous currents, before stopping a respectful distance away.

The three considered each other for a tense moment of detente before Harry used his translating bauble (as Alexio called it) to negotiate a truce.

The Chinese Wizard proclaimed no knowledge of a mirror, and sought only the Seven Virtuous Herbs. After a brief exchange, they agreed to keep well apart. With a whisk of his fan, the bubble moved away.

The pair had less luck with a Scandanavian witch with short-trimmed blonde hair, sharp glances and bony angles. After negotiations stretched past a quarter hour Alexio simply launched a bewildering array of hexes at the woman. They didn't get past her shields, but after overcoming his surprise Harry sighed and joined Alexio's attack, pausing only to ask what had led Alexio to act rashly.

"Few can withstand our combined onslaught," Alexio calmly explained as he twisted his wand and two moray eels appeared behind the witch, quickly wriggling through the water and then gnawing at her shields. Alexio did not bother stopping, and launched into another spell.

"Those who made it Atlantis are not randomly selected," Harry snarled.

But if the witch's talents were exceptional, they did not manifest during battle. A minute later she floated limply in the water, an annoyed look on her face. Harry turned to Alexio, who simply shrugged.

Harry murmured "Boring conversation, anyway," as he placed a small branch underneath the woman's arm and snapped it. Then she was gone and the water rushed into to fill the void left by her absence with a sharp thud as they surveyed the situation. They could make out distant forms - human forms - moving throughout Atlantis. Time had become an issue.

Harry pointed at a large building, with its columned foyer reaching out into the water looking for all the world like an inviting mouth opened into a lecherous smile. "There?" he asked and Alexio nodded.

"The Centro Civil," Alexio said, swimming towards the mouth. "It will be there, if legends speak true."

Alexio felt the wave of pressure as something swam past, and started casting instantly as though his wand were connected straight to his autonomic system, without active control of his higher functions. Harry, slightly slower, shouted Ventus then repeated the spell to his left and right. Before the third spell resolved Alexio had caught on and followed suit.

The simple spell - a child's spell, really - worked profoundly well underwater. The gust of wind instantly impacted the waiting water and cavitated into thousands of small bubbles that swirled and churned and spun chaotically.

The bubbles not only formed a visual shield and provided cover, the currents would flip and spin anyone caught inside. The bubbles also obscured Alexio's vision but not before he saw the flash of a limb where nothing had been before.

Now he had a target.

Alexio fired off two spells, the first a simple Lagann. A child's spell meant as a distraction. The second spell was in a language that Harry didn't understand, but the magic made him shudder. Harry felt the force of the spell, an Ecaudorian spell of pain and maiming Alexio had taken from a warlord who fancied himself a dark wizard.

Alexio took no chances against unseen threats, and was smoothly transitioning into a third spell even as Harry shouted at him to stop.

The spells streaked towards through the water and then slowed to a stop in front of the form slowly resolving as bubbles floated up and out of the way.

"You always did have terrible choices in friends, Harry Potter. Except for me, of course," Hermione Granger said, as she grabbed for something unseen and stuffed it into a backpack.

Alexio's jaw set. In the back of his mind, Draco almost dropped character as Hermione Granger gently tugged on the strands of his spell, pulling it apart before looking up at them.

"So. Who's your friend?" Hermione asked as she made a flicking motion with her wand. Alexio's glowing spell throbbed angrily, then streaked away as though shot from a cannon, before disappearing up into the shimmering blue light overhead.

"Alexio, Hermione Granger," Harry said while waving hands between the two of them. "Hermione, just so you know we're in ... I don't know, a fixed point in time. Alexio and I come from different eras. Judging from the looks of you, I'd say you were from my past. Distant past."

Alexio looked at Hermione while she considered this, and Draco peeked out through his eyes. He hadn't seen her in the flesh since they'd been children.

Alexio had arranged to never share her presence during the Grand Convocation, when he'd trapped Harry. Hermione had somehow escaped. Of course she'd escaped, even when Harry hadn't. While he'd never seen her since the days of Hogwarts, the Girl-Who-Revived's celebrity status allowed Alexio to track her for decades without arousing the slightest suspicion. Hermione Granger's fans numbered in the millions, she'd had dozen of stalkers, and political operatives with any sense the world over followed her movements.

It would have seemed suspicious if a man in his position hadn't tracked her. Alexio had plenty of images of adult-Hermione to compare to.

That didn't make it easier. Hermione seemed practically ageless, once she'd reached adulthood. He couldn't tell. She hadn't seemed surprised to see Harry alive. On the other hand, she'd seen them first and may have gotten over her shock before deciding to play her prank. Had she not realized that sneaking up on them would provoke an attack? Impossible. Perhaps she worried that it was not actually Harry, some imposter with Polyjuice. Perhaps she worried he'd been Imperiused. It was too much. Too many variables to consider. And the "terrible choice of friends," was that barb directed at Alexio? Or Draco?

Alexio suspected that this version of Hermione predated his attack on Harry. He couldn't be sure. If she was younger, from his past, then she'd accumulated power at a rate that made him envious. Then again, she hadn't hid and built her powerbase from scratch. Alexio looked down towards the ocean floor beneath them, considering, as she answered Harry.

"That makes sense. From what you told me Chang's Process of the Timeless trapped Dumbledore. Wherever he is should be timeless, too," Hermione said as she swam down between them. Harry and Alexio swam smoothly, but it seemed like Hermione just willed herself into place with subtle gestures.

The effect was unsettling.

"So, Alexio," she asked, ignoring Harry, "What brings you to Atlantis?"

"I warn you, Hermione Granger," Alexio said, packing the words with as much machismo as he dared, "I am a married man."

Hermione glared at him, but didn't say anything, which was always a fine tactic for revealing little. Alexio laughed. "I apologize. I could not resist. It is just that you sounded like a pickup line."

Harry spoke up, quietly but firmly. "Alexio is here to rescue Dumbledore, like I am."

"Like we are," Hermione said, with a look of determination.

They swam along. As they came to the entrance, a submersible all rigid bubbles placed at impossible angles swam by. A surprised looking woman stared at them through a viewport. The angles distorted her face monstrously, like a funhouse mirror. Alexio suspected that device could handle depths much deeper than the coastal plains they were swimming through. A robotic arm waved hello and scrolling text appeared along the side that seemed to be an introduction in broken english, but there were letters Draco didn't recognize, and accents marks.

Harry shook his head and they ducked into the building.

"When he had so spoken,

I beheld the Angel,

who stretched out his arms,

embracing the flame of fire

& he was consumed

and arose as Elijah"

The three of them stared at the waterfall flowing rapidly through the transom in a thick billowing curtain. Behind the falls, which looked to be merely a foot thick, they could see an archway, and through the archway stood the back of the mirror. Alexio stared at it, looking exactly the same as it had so long ago. It was no more than fifty feet from them, but they were separated from it by the waterfall. Water flowed from just below the ceiling down to the floor and bounced in crashing waves of unnaturally cerulean blues. Vivid hallucinatory blues that bounced once or twice across the marble floor before disappearing. Blues that spoke of beaches and skies.

And if the waterfall noticed that the entire structure was underwater, that it flowed through ocean water instead of air, it gave no indication.

"It's like one of those hypnotic wave machines from my childhood, with two colours of water that never mix but just rock back and forth," Hermione offered.

"We could go through the transom," Harry said, but he sounded dubious. The water flowed out of the transom but there was a gap above the water. A small gap. It seemed so obvious to swim through the gap that it must be a trap, which meant that perhaps it wasn't.

"I doubt Hermione would fit. Myself? Never." Alexio said. He had half a foot over Harry Potter, and at least one hundred pounds. Probably more.

None of them approached the flowing water, or had approached close enough to risk getting splashed by any of the droplets. They'd cast a variety of spells in numerous languages. None even registered the waterfall's existence or affected it in any way. Harry had stopped looking at the waterfall and was now examining the rest of the room.

"If you don't mind my asking," Alexio said.

"We're not supposed to. Temporal Paradoxes and whatnot," Hermione shot back.

"No, not your past. Just ... where did you learn to stop spells? Physically stop them?"

"Hogwarts, of course. The famous David Monroe," she saw by his look that he'd heard of him. Most of the Wizarding world had, in the years following Harry's second defeat of Voldemort.

"David Monroe taught you that?" Alexio said, sounding amazed.

"Well... not exactly. He showed me it could be done," Hermione admitted. "I worked out the details on my own. What did you find, Harry?" she added, because Harry was waving them over. They swam to a side wall, which was covered in runes. Obscure runes, older yet similar to anything he'd studied. Alexio felt like he knew them. He realized he did know them, even though he'd never seen them before.

Runes that definitely had not been there when they first arrived.

"Negation," Harry said, pointing to the rune at Twelve o'clock.

"Identity." Draco said, pointing to the Rune at Three o'clock.

"Perfection," Hermoine said, not bothering to point at the Six o'clock rune.

"Unity," Harry finished. Nine o'clock.

"You never took Runes, Harry," Hermione said reproachfully.

"But I know what they mean," Harry said. "I don't understand it. I've encountered this before, but its definitely Atlantean magic. Not the same as before, but similar. Knowledge, without really understanding."

"I feel it, too. Your translation feels roughly right. Not correct, but how Harry James Potter would describe those runes. Each rune has too many meanings. Its like Ancient Chinese, each word could be a verb or a noun, singular or plural. In any case, its a contradiction. 'Negation is perfect unity' doesn't make sense."

Alexio looked at the runes, which to him felt like poetry and not maths.

Hermione started listing off interpretations "'Reversing the Self creates the universe', no. 'Opposing viewpoints resolve into answers', true but how does that help? 'Enemies are ...' I can't even figure out how to finish that, 'perfectly together.' That's more a mantra, like Imagine by Jon Lennon. 'Failure leads to true success.' It's like a bad philosophy."

Alexio smiled, as the translation coalesced in his mind.

"We now have a problem," Alexio interrupted. "For beyond this arch rests the mirror that has trapped Albus Dumbledore. Once we swim through it, Who shall he return with?"

"I'm the obvious choice, assuming that I'm correct in the most future timeline," Harry said, automatically. "To send him to my past presents problems."

"Ah, but Albus Dumbledore may be confused by the changes. No, he should go to the newest timeline, and hide himself from us until later," Alexio added. "We can tell him, before we depart, from when we each came."

"Why does he have to go to our time? Perhaps he's secretly Merlin?" Hermione said. "In any case, you seem to be ignoring the obvious problem of how we're going to get past this enchanted waterfall. Not to mention freeing the Headmaster."

"I cannot get past it," Alexio said. "But we? We three can simply swim through it together. After that, well, we each had a plan to free Dumbledore. At least one will work. I have no doubt."

"You got that from the Runes? That doesn't make sense."

"Unlike you, I am not always rational," Alexio admitted. "In my defense, I have the soul of a poet. And I have read this poem elsewhere - in English, no less! I think the Atlanteans, whatever else they were, understood people. They had a nobility, and these runes are a proclamation of it. It is not a warning. They have never threatened us. The real danger here has been others. Those wizards and witches we have seen. The Atlanteans will not hurt us, although they may vex us."

"You could sooner destroy the world with a block of cheese," Harry said. Alexio did not take the meaning, but he could see that Hermione did.

"You aren't serious considering this, Harry?" she asked.

Alexio smiled. "If you like, I can go first. If the falls consume me horribly, then you will know."

"Why are you smiling?" Hermione asked. Even though she was surrounded by a bubble head charm, the words escaped like hisses bubbling away.

"Because I have hope, and hope has been precious rare to me for some time. I prefer my translation to yours. You have captured the words, but not the essence."

"What is the translation?" Harry asked.

"I cannot tell her," Alexio said sheepishly. "There is information she must not have. Not yet."

Hermione glanced between the two of them, then abruptly spun and swam away to the other side of the room. Alexio cast several spells to ensure that he could not be heard, and Harry cast a few of his own, then put down his wand. Hermione could see them leaning together, just for a second, but the spells cancelled all communication, not just sounds. She couldn't make out the large man's lips as he spoke a few words. They had a conversation that lasted several minutes, but she couldn't read anything from it. She couldn't make out any detail at all that gave her a clue, it was a rare and infuriating experience.

Hermione saw them reverse their spells and swam back.

"I'm satisfied," Harry said.

"You can't be! It doesn't make sense. This isn't like you, Harry!"

"This isn't like me from your time, true. But I have privileged information. As Alexio has inferred, I know quite a bit about my past and your future. He explained his rationale for his actions, and gave me a nice translation that seems to be more than coincidence."

"At least tell me the source," Hermione said.

"For anyone else I would consider it, but you're too well read and with your memory ... well, you might make a few inductive leaps and then I've upset the timeline ... Anyway, you know how Time Turners work. All the laws of time travel indicate neither of you die or are seriously injured at the time. That, coupled with what I know about the mirror, makes me think think that worst case? We'll all pop back into where we came from. Have any of you ever heard of anyone questing for Atlantis and suffering physical harm? My research hasn't"

"A Scandanavian witch, Mamseil Arfvidsson, said that during her trip to Atlantis she was attacked by a pair of demons, one monstrous and terrifying the other delicate and cunning ... oh Harry," she folded her arms and glared at the two of them but mainly Harry Potter.

"We weren't that bad," Harry said. "We just stunned her."

"She started it," Alexio chimed in, shrugging his shoulders. "Indirectly, perhaps. No doubt she exaggerated to bolster her reputation and salvage something from the expedition."

"Well, If you two fools are going to go first, I hardly see any reason to wait around."

Alexio held out his hand and led the trio through the doorway, and as the water crashed around him, he smiled. He didn't know what the future held, but he had hope.

Harry smiled at both of them. "After we're finished, I have no idea what I'll do for fun."

Hermione just snorted bubbles, gently blowing her hair from out of her face. "I imagine you'll find something ... annoying," she said, as the swam off together towards the mirror.

"Note. This Angel,

who is now become a Devil,

is my particular friend."

- William Blake, The Marriage of Heaven and Hell

Author's Note - This ends my epilogue, which I conceived about a half year ago as a way to continue my story (slightly) and also try to answer lingering questions on Draco's motivations and beliefs. I have beliefs (rather firm ones) about how the story continues, but these beliefs aren't about any specific facts as to "how" things happen, but about how the Trinity view each other.

I did not intend DMPOR as a depressing story, though some took it that way. The William Blake quotes contain much more of my true beliefs than I had imagined possible. (And, just for the record, I wrote my draft - with interspersed quotes - prior to the publication of the Significant Digits epilogue, which I was terrified would also have the rescue of Albus Dumbledore as a plot device. So, I dodged one bullet, but the similarity of running quotes is duplicated. Ah well.)

If you look through The Marriage of Heaven and Hell, you will find Draco's translation of the Atlantean Runes and understand why their appearance gave him hope. I tried to work it into the story, but the writing was clumsy, and after several months I cut it out and it works better if the reader fills in the details. But I have been too opaque in the past, hence this note.

Update 9/8 - It turns out that what I thought was the quote in MoHH is (in fact) not in every copy, and may just be the title of one of the engravings. It is listed in some copies, but not others. Given that, here is the quote in Rot13: Bccbfvgvba vf gehr sevraqfuvc